{"nodes":[{"content":"Represents an object that describes the customizations to the non-client area of a window.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,90],"content":"Represents an object that describes the customizations to the non-client area of a window.","nodes":[{"content":"Represents an object that describes the customizations to the non-client area of a window.","pos":[0,90]}]}],"pos":[2079,2170],"yaml":true},{"content":"The                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class enables you to extend Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) content into the non-client area of a window that is typically reserved for the operating system’s window manager.  \n  \n## Standard Windows  \n Standard windows are composed of two overlapping rectangles. The outer rectangle is the                                  *non-client area*, which is often referred to as                                  *chrome*. It is drawn and managed by the operating system’s window manager. Its dimensions are determined by standard operating system settings. The non-client frame provides standard window features and behaviors. These include caption buttons (Minimize, Maximize, and Close), the window border, resize and move behaviors, the application icon and title, and the system menu. The inner rectangle is the                                  *client area*. It contains the contents of your application, and it is drawn and managed by the application. For more information about windows in WPF applications, see                                  [WPF Windows Overview](~/docs/framework/wpf/app-development/wpf-windows-overview.md).  \n  \n The following illustration shows the parts of a standard window.  \n  \n ![Window elements](~/add/media/windowoverviewfigure1.PNG \"Window elements\")  \n  \n## Custom Windows  \n You can customize a window border by setting the                                  <xref:System.Windows.Window.WindowStyle%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property to                                  <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle.None> or by using the                                  <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class.  \n  \n### WindowStyle.None  \n One way to customize the appearance of a WPF application window is to set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Window.WindowStyle%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property to                                          <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle.None>. This removes the non-client frame from the window and leaves only the client area, to which you can apply a custom style. However, when the non-client frame is removed, you also lose the system features and behaviors that it provides, such as caption buttons and window resizing. Another side effect is that the window will cover the Windows taskbar when it is maximized. Setting                                          <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle?displayProperty=fullName> enables you to create a completely custom application, but also requires that you implement custom logic in your application to emulate standard window behavior.  \n  \n### WindowChrome  \n To customize a window while retaining its standard functionality, you can use the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class. The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class separates the functionality of the window frame from the visuals, and lets you control the boundary between the client and non-client areas of your application window. The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class lets you put WPF content in the window frame by extending the client area to cover the non-client area. At the same time, it retains system behaviors through two invisible areas; the                                          *resize border* and                                          *caption* areas                                         .  \n  \n There are                                          two main parts                                          to creating a custom window using the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class. First, you customize the non-client part of the window by setting properties exposed on the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> object. Then you provide a template for the window that defines the part of your application that is extended into the non-client area.The properties exposed on the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> object are                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A>,                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A>,                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A>, and                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A>.  \n  \n The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> property specifies an invisible border around the outside of the application window that the user can click-and-drag to resize the window.  \n  \n The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property specifies an invisible area at the top of the window that enables system behaviors typically associated with the title bar. These behaviors include: click and drag to move the window, double-click to maximize the window, and right-click to show the system menu.  \n  \n The resize border and caption area do not have any visual elements; they only define areas that respond to input and enable standard system-provided window behaviors.  \n  \n The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> property specifies the amount that the corners of the window are rounded. This property does not have any effect if the glass frame is enabled for a window.  \n  \n The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property specifies the width of the glass frame around the window. By default, it uses the system value specified by the                                          <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.WindowNonClientFrameThickness%2A> property to emulate the appearance of a standard window. When the glass frame is used, the caption buttons for Minimize, Maximize, and Close are visible and interactive. The application is responsible for displaying the application icon and caption text. You can set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to make the glass frame wider or narrower than the default.  \n  \n> [!CAUTION]\n>  The size of the caption buttons does not change when the                                              <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is changed. If the height of the top of the glass frame is less than the height of the caption buttons, the caption buttons will not be completely visible.  \n  \n To make a custom window that does not have a glass frame, set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a uniform value of 0. This will disable and hide the standard caption buttons.  \n  \n To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a negative value on any side. When the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>.  \n  \n> [!NOTE]\n>  Aero is a set of visual enhancements to the look and functionality of the Windows desktop that was introduced in Windows Vista. One of the more visually obvious features of Aero is translucent glass window borders. Windows Aero is enabled by the desktop composition feature of the Desktop Window Manager (DWM).  \n  \n Windows Aero glass effects are not supported on all operating systems, and can be disabled on supported operating systems. If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property value. The border area specified by this property will appear black instead.Check the                                          <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available. If glass effects are not available, you should provide an alternate window style that does not use the glass frame or use the standard window by setting the window style to null.  \n  \n You extend your WPF content into the window frame by specifying a ControlTemplate that defines the appearance and behavior of the frame content. You set the TargetType of the ControlTemplate to the type of the window that you are customizing.  \n  \n```  \n<ControlTemplate TargetType=\"{x:Type local:MainWindow}\">  \n```  \n  \n By default, the parts of any visual elements that are within the non-client area of the window are not interactive. To enable interactive elements in the non-client area, attach the WindowsChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome attached property to the element and set it to true.  \n  \n The following XAML markup shows the main elements needed to customize a window using the WindowChrome class.  \n  \n```  \n<Style x:Key=\"StandardStyle\" TargetType=\"{x:Type local:MainWindow}\">  \n    <Setter Property=\"shell:WindowChrome.WindowChrome\">  \n        <Setter.Value>  \n            <shell:WindowChrome />  \n        </Setter.Value>  \n    </Setter>  \n    <Setter Property=\"Template\">  \n        <Setter.Value>  \n            <ControlTemplate TargetType=\"{x:Type local:MainWindow}\">  \n                <Grid>  \n                    <Border Background=\"White\"  \n                            Margin=\"{Binding Source={x:Static shell:SystemParameters2.Current}, Path=WindowNonClientFrameThickness}\">  \n                        <ContentPresenter Content=\"{TemplateBinding Content}\" />  \n                    </Border>  \n                    <TextBlock Text=\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=Title}\"   \n                               VerticalAlignment=\"Top\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Left\"   \n                               Margin=\"36,8,0,0\"/>  \n                    <Image Source=\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=Icon}\"  \n                           VerticalAlignment=\"Top\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Left\"  \n                           Margin=\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=(shell:WindowChrome.WindowChrome).ResizeBorderThickness}\"   \n                           Width=\"{Binding Source={x:Static shell:SystemParameters2.Current}, Path=SmallIconSize.Width}\"  \n                           shell:WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome=\"True\"/>  \n                </Grid>  \n            </ControlTemplate>  \n        </Setter.Value>  \n    </Setter>  \n</Style>  \n```  \n  \n The first setter attaches the WindowChrome to the window. It uses all default values for the WindowChrome properties, which makes the window look like a standard window.  \n  \n```  \n<Setter Property=\"shell:WindowChrome.WindowChrome\">  \n    <Setter.Value>  \n        <shell:WindowChrome />  \n    </Setter.Value>  \n</Setter>  \n```  \n  \n The window template must specify a content presenter to display the contents of the window specified in your application. By default the WindowChrome class extends the client area to cover the non-client border. In order to uncover the glass frame, you need to specify a margin around the ContentPresenter. This markup specifies a border with a white background around the content presenter to emulate the appearance of a standard window. It also specifies a margin that is bound to the WindowNonClientFrameThickness property, which gets the default system width for the frame.  \n  \n```  \n<Border Background=\"White\"  \n    Margin=\"{Binding Source={x:Static shell:SystemParameters2.Current}, Path=WindowNonClientFrameThickness}\">  \n    <ContentPresenter Content=\"{TemplateBinding Content}\" />  \n</Border>  \n```  \n  \n The application icon and title are not displayed by the WindowChrome class; they have to be added to the border as custom content. The following XAML adds an image and a textblock to display the icon and title. Both elements are bound to the corresponding properties on the window. The image width is bound to the SmallIconSize width, which gets the default system size for the icon. The IsHitTestVisibleInChrome attached property is set on the image so that it can receive mouse events.  \n  \n```  \n<Image Source=\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=Icon}\"  \n       VerticalAlignment=\"Top\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Left\"  \n       Margin=\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=(shell:WindowChrome.WindowChrome).ResizeBorderThickness}\"   \n       Width=\"{Binding Source={x:Static shell:SystemParameters2.Current}, Path=SmallIconSize.Width}\"  \n       shell:WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome=\"True\"/>  \n  \n<TextBlock Text=\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=Title}\"   \n           VerticalAlignment=\"Top\" HorizontalAlignment=\"Left\"   \n           Margin=\"36,8,0,0\"/>  \n```","nodes":[{"pos":[0,250],"content":"The                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class enables you to extend Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) content into the non-client area of a window that is typically reserved for the operating system’s window manager.","nodes":[{"content":"The                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome&gt;</ph> class enables you to extend Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) content into the non-client area of a window that is typically reserved for the operating system’s window manager.","pos":[0,250],"source":"The                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class enables you to extend Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) content into the non-client area of a window that is typically reserved for the operating system’s window manager."}]},{"pos":[259,275],"content":"Standard Windows","linkify":"Standard Windows","nodes":[{"content":"Standard Windows","pos":[0,16]}]},{"pos":[279,1206],"content":"Standard windows are composed of two overlapping rectangles. The outer rectangle is the                                  *non-client area*, which is often referred to as                                  *chrome*. It is drawn and managed by the operating system’s window manager. Its dimensions are determined by standard operating system settings. The non-client frame provides standard window features and behaviors. These include caption buttons (Minimize, Maximize, and Close), the window border, resize and move behaviors, the application icon and title, and the system menu. The inner rectangle is the                                  *client area*. It contains the contents of your application, and it is drawn and managed by the application. For more information about windows in WPF applications, see                                  [WPF Windows Overview](~/docs/framework/wpf/app-development/wpf-windows-overview.md).","nodes":[{"content":"Standard windows are composed of two overlapping rectangles.","pos":[0,60]},{"content":"The outer rectangle is the                                  <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>non-client area<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>, which is often referred to as                                  <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>chrome<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>.","pos":[61,212],"source":" The outer rectangle is the                                  *non-client area*, which is often referred to as                                  *chrome*."},{"content":"It is drawn and managed by the operating system’s window manager.","pos":[213,278]},{"content":"Its dimensions are determined by standard operating system settings.","pos":[279,347]},{"content":"The non-client frame provides standard window features and behaviors.","pos":[348,417]},{"content":"These include caption buttons (Minimize, Maximize, and Close), the window border, resize and move behaviors, the application icon and title, and the system menu.","pos":[418,579]},{"content":"The inner rectangle is the                                  <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>client area<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.","pos":[580,654],"source":" The inner rectangle is the                                  *client area*."},{"content":"It contains the contents of your application, and it is drawn and managed by the application.","pos":[655,748]},{"content":"For more information about windows in WPF applications, see                                  <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>WPF Windows Overview<ept id=\"p1\">](~/docs/framework/wpf/app-development/wpf-windows-overview.md)</ept>.","pos":[749,927],"source":" For more information about windows in WPF applications, see                                  [WPF Windows Overview](~/docs/framework/wpf/app-development/wpf-windows-overview.md)."}]},{"pos":[1213,1277],"content":"The following illustration shows the parts of a standard window.","nodes":[{"content":"The following illustration shows the parts of a standard window.","pos":[0,64]}]},{"pos":[1284,1359],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">![</bpt>Window elements<ept id=\"p1\">]</ept><bpt id=\"p2\">(~/add/media/windowoverviewfigure1.PNG \"</bpt>Window elements<ept id=\"p2\">\")</ept>","source":"![Window elements](~/add/media/windowoverviewfigure1.PNG \"Window elements\")"},{"pos":[1368,1382],"content":"Custom Windows","linkify":"Custom Windows","nodes":[{"content":"Custom Windows","pos":[0,14]}]},{"pos":[1386,1717],"content":"You can customize a window border by setting the                                  <xref:System.Windows.Window.WindowStyle%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property to                                  <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle.None> or by using the                                  <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class.","nodes":[{"content":"You can customize a window border by setting the                                  <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Window.WindowStyle%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> property to                                  <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle.None&gt;</ph> or by using the                                  <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome&gt;</ph> class.","pos":[0,331],"source":"You can customize a window border by setting the                                  <xref:System.Windows.Window.WindowStyle%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property to                                  <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle.None> or by using the                                  <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class."}]},{"pos":[1727,1743],"content":"WindowStyle.None","linkify":"WindowStyle.None","nodes":[{"content":"WindowStyle.None","pos":[0,16]}]},{"pos":[1747,2669],"content":"One way to customize the appearance of a WPF application window is to set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Window.WindowStyle%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property to                                          <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle.None>. This removes the non-client frame from the window and leaves only the client area, to which you can apply a custom style. However, when the non-client frame is removed, you also lose the system features and behaviors that it provides, such as caption buttons and window resizing. Another side effect is that the window will cover the Windows taskbar when it is maximized. Setting                                          <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle?displayProperty=fullName> enables you to create a completely custom application, but also requires that you implement custom logic in your application to emulate standard window behavior.","nodes":[{"content":"One way to customize the appearance of a WPF application window is to set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Window.WindowStyle%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property to                                          <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle.None>. This removes the non-client frame from the window and leaves only the client area, to which you can apply a custom style. However, when the non-client frame is removed, you also lose the system features and behaviors that it provides, such as caption buttons and window resizing. Another side effect is that the window will cover the Windows taskbar when it is maximized. Setting                                          <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle?displayProperty=fullName> enables you to create a completely custom application, but also requires that you implement custom logic in your application to emulate standard window behavior.","pos":[0,922],"nodes":[{"content":"One way to customize the appearance of a WPF application window is to set the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Window.WindowStyle%2A?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> property to                                          <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle.None&gt;</ph>.","pos":[0,280],"source":"One way to customize the appearance of a WPF application window is to set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Window.WindowStyle%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property to                                          <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle.None>."},{"content":"This removes the non-client frame from the window and leaves only the client area, to which you can apply a custom style.","pos":[281,402]},{"content":"However, when the non-client frame is removed, you also lose the system features and behaviors that it provides, such as caption buttons and window resizing.","pos":[403,560]},{"content":"Another side effect is that the window will cover the Windows taskbar when it is maximized.","pos":[561,652]},{"content":"Setting                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle?displayProperty=fullName&gt;</ph> enables you to create a completely custom application, but also requires that you implement custom logic in your application to emulate standard window behavior.","pos":[653,922],"source":" Setting                                          <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle?displayProperty=fullName> enables you to create a completely custom application, but also requires that you implement custom logic in your application to emulate standard window behavior."}]}]},{"pos":[2679,2691],"content":"WindowChrome","linkify":"WindowChrome","nodes":[{"content":"WindowChrome","pos":[0,12]}]},{"pos":[2695,3560],"content":"To customize a window while retaining its standard functionality, you can use the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class. The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class separates the functionality of the window frame from the visuals, and lets you control the boundary between the client and non-client areas of your application window. The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class lets you put WPF content in the window frame by extending the client area to cover the non-client area. At the same time, it retains system behaviors through two invisible areas; the                                          *resize border* and                                          *caption* areas                                         .","nodes":[{"content":"To customize a window while retaining its standard functionality, you can use the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome&gt;</ph> class.","pos":[0,170],"source":"To customize a window while retaining its standard functionality, you can use the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class."},{"content":"The                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome&gt;</ph> class separates the functionality of the window frame from the visuals, and lets you control the boundary between the client and non-client areas of your application window.","pos":[171,430],"source":" The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class separates the functionality of the window frame from the visuals, and lets you control the boundary between the client and non-client areas of your application window."},{"content":"The                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome&gt;</ph> class lets you put WPF content in the window frame by extending the client area to cover the non-client area.","pos":[431,626],"source":" The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class lets you put WPF content in the window frame by extending the client area to cover the non-client area."},{"content":"At the same time, it retains system behaviors through two invisible areas; the                                          <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>resize border<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> and                                          <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>caption<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept> areas                                         .","pos":[627,865],"source":" At the same time, it retains system behaviors through two invisible areas; the                                          *resize border* and                                          *caption* areas                                         ."}]},{"pos":[3567,4649],"content":"There are                                          two main parts                                          to creating a custom window using the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class. First, you customize the non-client part of the window by setting properties exposed on the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> object. Then you provide a template for the window that defines the part of your application that is extended into the non-client area.The properties exposed on the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> object are                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A>,                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A>,                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A>, and                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A>.","nodes":[{"content":"There are                                          two main parts                                          to creating a custom window using the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class. First, you customize the non-client part of the window by setting properties exposed on the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> object. Then you provide a template for the window that defines the part of your application that is extended into the non-client area.The properties exposed on the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> object are                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A>,                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A>,                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A>, and                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A>.","pos":[0,1082],"nodes":[{"content":"There are                                          two main parts                                          to creating a custom window using the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome&gt;</ph> class.","pos":[0,233],"source":"There are                                          two main parts                                          to creating a custom window using the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class."},{"content":"First, you customize the non-client part of the window by setting properties exposed on the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome&gt;</ph> object.","pos":[234,415],"source":" First, you customize the non-client part of the window by setting properties exposed on the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> object."},{"content":"Then you provide a template for the window that defines the part of your application that is extended into the non-client area.The properties exposed on the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome&gt;</ph> object are                                          <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A&gt;</ph>,                                          <ph id=\"ph3\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A&gt;</ph>,                                          <ph id=\"ph4\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A&gt;</ph>, and                                          <ph id=\"ph5\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph>.","pos":[416,1082],"source":" Then you provide a template for the window that defines the part of your application that is extended into the non-client area.The properties exposed on the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> object are                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A>,                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A>,                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A>, and                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A>."}]}]},{"pos":[4656,4905],"content":"The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> property specifies an invisible border around the outside of the application window that the user can click-and-drag to resize the window.","nodes":[{"content":"The                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property specifies an invisible border around the outside of the application window that the user can click-and-drag to resize the window.","pos":[0,249],"source":"The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> property specifies an invisible border around the outside of the application window that the user can click-and-drag to resize the window."}]},{"pos":[4912,5285],"content":"The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property specifies an invisible area at the top of the window that enables system behaviors typically associated with the title bar. These behaviors include: click and drag to move the window, double-click to maximize the window, and right-click to show the system menu.","nodes":[{"content":"The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property specifies an invisible area at the top of the window that enables system behaviors typically associated with the title bar. These behaviors include: click and drag to move the window, double-click to maximize the window, and right-click to show the system menu.","pos":[0,373],"nodes":[{"content":"The                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A&gt;</ph> property specifies an invisible area at the top of the window that enables system behaviors typically associated with the title bar.","pos":[0,235],"source":"The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property specifies an invisible area at the top of the window that enables system behaviors typically associated with the title bar."},{"content":"These behaviors include: click and drag to move the window, double-click to maximize the window, and right-click to show the system menu.","pos":[236,373]}]}]},{"pos":[5292,5458],"content":"The resize border and caption area do not have any visual elements; they only define areas that respond to input and enable standard system-provided window behaviors.","nodes":[{"content":"The resize border and caption area do not have any visual elements; they only define areas that respond to input and enable standard system-provided window behaviors.","pos":[0,166]}]},{"pos":[5465,5723],"content":"The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> property specifies the amount that the corners of the window are rounded. This property does not have any effect if the glass frame is enabled for a window.","nodes":[{"content":"The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> property specifies the amount that the corners of the window are rounded. This property does not have any effect if the glass frame is enabled for a window.","pos":[0,258],"nodes":[{"content":"The                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A&gt;</ph> property specifies the amount that the corners of the window are rounded.","pos":[0,175],"source":"The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> property specifies the amount that the corners of the window are rounded."},{"content":"This property does not have any effect if the glass frame is enabled for a window.","pos":[176,258]}]}]},{"pos":[5730,6517],"content":"The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property specifies the width of the glass frame around the window. By default, it uses the system value specified by the                                          <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.WindowNonClientFrameThickness%2A> property to emulate the appearance of a standard window. When the glass frame is used, the caption buttons for Minimize, Maximize, and Close are visible and interactive. The application is responsible for displaying the application icon and caption text. You can set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to make the glass frame wider or narrower than the default.","nodes":[{"content":"The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property specifies the width of the glass frame around the window. By default, it uses the system value specified by the                                          <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.WindowNonClientFrameThickness%2A> property to emulate the appearance of a standard window. When the glass frame is used, the caption buttons for Minimize, Maximize, and Close are visible and interactive. The application is responsible for displaying the application icon and caption text. You can set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to make the glass frame wider or narrower than the default.","pos":[0,787],"nodes":[{"content":"The                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property specifies the width of the glass frame around the window.","pos":[0,175],"source":"The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property specifies the width of the glass frame around the window."},{"content":"By default, it uses the system value specified by the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.WindowNonClientFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property to emulate the appearance of a standard window.","pos":[176,399],"source":" By default, it uses the system value specified by the                                          <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.WindowNonClientFrameThickness%2A> property to emulate the appearance of a standard window."},{"content":"When the glass frame is used, the caption buttons for Minimize, Maximize, and Close are visible and interactive.","pos":[400,512]},{"content":"The application is responsible for displaying the application icon and caption text.","pos":[513,597]},{"content":"You can set the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property to make the glass frame wider or narrower than the default.","pos":[598,787],"source":" You can set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to make the glass frame wider or narrower than the default."}]}]},{"pos":[6525,6869],"content":"[!CAUTION]\n The size of the caption buttons does not change when the                                              <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is changed. If the height of the top of the glass frame is less than the height of the caption buttons, the caption buttons will not be completely visible.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":" The size of the caption buttons does not change when the                                              <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is changed. If the height of the top of the glass frame is less than the height of the caption buttons, the caption buttons will not be completely visible.","pos":[11,342],"nodes":[{"content":"The size of the caption buttons does not change when the                                              <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property is changed.","pos":[1,187],"source":" The size of the caption buttons does not change when the                                              <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is changed."},{"content":"If the height of the top of the glass frame is less than the height of the caption buttons, the caption buttons will not be completely visible.","pos":[188,331]}]}]},{"pos":[6876,7137],"content":"To make a custom window that does not have a glass frame, set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a uniform value of 0. This will disable and hide the standard caption buttons.","nodes":[{"content":"To make a custom window that does not have a glass frame, set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a uniform value of 0. This will disable and hide the standard caption buttons.","pos":[0,261],"nodes":[{"content":"To make a custom window that does not have a glass frame, set the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property to a uniform value of 0.","pos":[0,204],"source":"To make a custom window that does not have a glass frame, set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a uniform value of 0."},{"content":"This will disable and hide the standard caption buttons.","pos":[205,261]}]}]},{"pos":[7144,7665],"content":"To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a negative value on any side. When the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>.","nodes":[{"content":"To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a negative value on any side. When the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>.","pos":[0,521],"nodes":[{"content":"To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property to a negative value on any side.","pos":[0,208],"source":"To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a negative value on any side."},{"content":"When the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to                                          <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A&gt;</ph>.","pos":[209,521],"source":" When the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>."}]}]},{"pos":[7673,7994],"content":"[!NOTE]\n Aero is a set of visual enhancements to the look and functionality of the Windows desktop that was introduced in Windows Vista. One of the more visually obvious features of Aero is translucent glass window borders. Windows Aero is enabled by the desktop composition feature of the Desktop Window Manager (DWM).","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":" Aero is a set of visual enhancements to the look and functionality of the Windows desktop that was introduced in Windows Vista. One of the more visually obvious features of Aero is translucent glass window borders. Windows Aero is enabled by the desktop composition feature of the Desktop Window Manager (DWM).","pos":[8,319],"nodes":[{"content":"Aero is a set of visual enhancements to the look and functionality of the Windows desktop that was introduced in Windows Vista.","pos":[1,128]},{"content":"One of the more visually obvious features of Aero is translucent glass window borders.","pos":[129,215]},{"content":"Windows Aero is enabled by the desktop composition feature of the Desktop Window Manager (DWM).","pos":[216,311]}]}]},{"pos":[8001,8756],"content":"Windows Aero glass effects are not supported on all operating systems, and can be disabled on supported operating systems. If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property value. The border area specified by this property will appear black instead.Check the                                          <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available. If glass effects are not available, you should provide an alternate window style that does not use the glass frame or use the standard window by setting the window style to null.","nodes":[{"content":"Windows Aero glass effects are not supported on all operating systems, and can be disabled on supported operating systems. If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property value. The border area specified by this property will appear black instead.Check the                                          <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available. If glass effects are not available, you should provide an alternate window style that does not use the glass frame or use the standard window by setting the window style to null.","pos":[0,755],"nodes":[{"content":"Windows Aero glass effects are not supported on all operating systems, and can be disabled on supported operating systems.","pos":[0,122]},{"content":"If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property value.","pos":[123,333],"source":" If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property value."},{"content":"The border area specified by this property will appear black instead.Check the                                          <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A&gt;</ph> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available.","pos":[334,576],"source":" The border area specified by this property will appear black instead.Check the                                          <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available."},{"content":"If glass effects are not available, you should provide an alternate window style that does not use the glass frame or use the standard window by setting the window style to null.","pos":[577,755]}]}]},{"pos":[8763,9005],"content":"You extend your WPF content into the window frame by specifying a ControlTemplate that defines the appearance and behavior of the frame content. You set the TargetType of the ControlTemplate to the type of the window that you are customizing.","nodes":[{"content":"You extend your WPF content into the window frame by specifying a ControlTemplate that defines the appearance and behavior of the frame content. You set the TargetType of the ControlTemplate to the type of the window that you are customizing.","pos":[0,242],"nodes":[{"content":"You extend your WPF content into the window frame by specifying a ControlTemplate that defines the appearance and behavior of the frame content.","pos":[0,144]},{"content":"You set the TargetType of the ControlTemplate to the type of the window that you are customizing.","pos":[145,242]}]}]},{"pos":[9086,9359],"content":"By default, the parts of any visual elements that are within the non-client area of the window are not interactive. To enable interactive elements in the non-client area, attach the WindowsChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome attached property to the element and set it to true.","nodes":[{"content":"By default, the parts of any visual elements that are within the non-client area of the window are not interactive. To enable interactive elements in the non-client area, attach the WindowsChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome attached property to the element and set it to true.","pos":[0,273],"nodes":[{"content":"By default, the parts of any visual elements that are within the non-client area of the window are not interactive.","pos":[0,115]},{"content":"To enable interactive elements in the non-client area, attach the WindowsChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome attached property to the element and set it to true.","pos":[116,273]}]}]},{"pos":[9366,9474],"content":"The following XAML markup shows the main elements needed to customize a window using the WindowChrome class.","nodes":[{"content":"The following XAML markup shows the main elements needed to customize a window using the WindowChrome class.","pos":[0,108]}]},{"pos":[11097,11266],"content":"The first setter attaches the WindowChrome to the window. It uses all default values for the WindowChrome properties, which makes the window look like a standard window.","nodes":[{"content":"The first setter attaches the WindowChrome to the window. It uses all default values for the WindowChrome properties, which makes the window look like a standard window.","pos":[0,169],"nodes":[{"content":"The first setter attaches the WindowChrome to the window.","pos":[0,57]},{"content":"It uses all default values for the WindowChrome properties, which makes the window look like a standard window.","pos":[58,169]}]}]},{"pos":[11430,12007],"content":"The window template must specify a content presenter to display the contents of the window specified in your application. By default the WindowChrome class extends the client area to cover the non-client border. In order to uncover the glass frame, you need to specify a margin around the ContentPresenter. This markup specifies a border with a white background around the content presenter to emulate the appearance of a standard window. It also specifies a margin that is bound to the WindowNonClientFrameThickness property, which gets the default system width for the frame.","nodes":[{"content":"The window template must specify a content presenter to display the contents of the window specified in your application. By default the WindowChrome class extends the client area to cover the non-client border. In order to uncover the glass frame, you need to specify a margin around the ContentPresenter. This markup specifies a border with a white background around the content presenter to emulate the appearance of a standard window. It also specifies a margin that is bound to the WindowNonClientFrameThickness property, which gets the default system width for the frame.","pos":[0,577],"nodes":[{"content":"The window template must specify a content presenter to display the contents of the window specified in your application.","pos":[0,121]},{"content":"By default the WindowChrome class extends the client area to cover the non-client border.","pos":[122,211]},{"content":"In order to uncover the glass frame, you need to specify a margin around the ContentPresenter.","pos":[212,306]},{"content":"This markup specifies a border with a white background around the content presenter to emulate the appearance of a standard window.","pos":[307,438]},{"content":"It also specifies a margin that is bound to the WindowNonClientFrameThickness property, which gets the default system width for the frame.","pos":[439,577]}]}]},{"pos":[12245,12732],"content":"The application icon and title are not displayed by the WindowChrome class; they have to be added to the border as custom content. The following XAML adds an image and a textblock to display the icon and title. Both elements are bound to the corresponding properties on the window. The image width is bound to the SmallIconSize width, which gets the default system size for the icon. The IsHitTestVisibleInChrome attached property is set on the image so that it can receive mouse events.","nodes":[{"content":"The application icon and title are not displayed by the WindowChrome class; they have to be added to the border as custom content. The following XAML adds an image and a textblock to display the icon and title. Both elements are bound to the corresponding properties on the window. The image width is bound to the SmallIconSize width, which gets the default system size for the icon. The IsHitTestVisibleInChrome attached property is set on the image so that it can receive mouse events.","pos":[0,487],"nodes":[{"content":"The application icon and title are not displayed by the WindowChrome class; they have to be added to the border as custom content.","pos":[0,130]},{"content":"The following XAML adds an image and a textblock to display the icon and title.","pos":[131,210]},{"content":"Both elements are bound to the corresponding properties on the window.","pos":[211,281]},{"content":"The image width is bound to the SmallIconSize width, which gets the default system size for the icon.","pos":[282,383]},{"content":"The IsHitTestVisibleInChrome attached property is set on the image so that it can receive mouse events.","pos":[384,487]}]}]}],"pos":[2181,15755],"yaml":true,"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"Initializes a new instance of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> class.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,95],"content":"Initializes a new instance of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> class.","source":"Initializes a new instance of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> class."}],"pos":[19815,19911],"yaml":true},{"content":"Gets or sets the height of the caption area at the top of a window.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,67],"content":"Gets or sets the height of the caption area at the top of a window.","nodes":[{"content":"Gets or sets the height of the caption area at the top of a window.","pos":[0,67]}]}],"pos":[20961,21029],"yaml":true},{"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property to specify the area at the top of the window that enables the system behaviors typically associated with the title bar. These behaviors include double-click to maximize the window, right-click to open the system menu, and click-and-drag to move the window. This property can be set to any non-negative double value.  \n  \n The area defined by the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property starts at the bottom edge of the top resize border and extends downward the specified amount. It spans the width of the window inside the right and left resize borders. This area does not have any visual elements associated with it; it is only used to define the region that responds to the title bar behaviors. By default, the parts of any visual elements that are within the caption area of the window are not interactive. To enable interactive elements in the caption area, attach the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome%2A> attached property to the element and set it to `true`.  \n  \n<a name=\"dependencyPropertyInfo_CaptionHeight\"></a>   \n## Dependency Property Information  \n  \n|||  \n|-|-|  \n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeightProperty>|  \n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|","nodes":[{"pos":[0,390],"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property to specify the area at the top of the window that enables the system behaviors typically associated with the title bar. These behaviors include double-click to maximize the window, right-click to open the system menu, and click-and-drag to move the window. This property can be set to any non-negative double value.","nodes":[{"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property to specify the area at the top of the window that enables the system behaviors typically associated with the title bar. These behaviors include double-click to maximize the window, right-click to open the system menu, and click-and-drag to move the window. This property can be set to any non-negative double value.","pos":[0,390],"nodes":[{"content":"Set the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A&gt;</ph> property to specify the area at the top of the window that enables the system behaviors typically associated with the title bar.","pos":[0,194],"source":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property to specify the area at the top of the window that enables the system behaviors typically associated with the title bar."},{"content":"These behaviors include double-click to maximize the window, right-click to open the system menu, and click-and-drag to move the window.","pos":[195,331]},{"content":"This property can be set to any non-negative double value.","pos":[332,390]}]}]},{"pos":[397,1099],"content":"The area defined by the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property starts at the bottom edge of the top resize border and extends downward the specified amount. It spans the width of the window inside the right and left resize borders. This area does not have any visual elements associated with it; it is only used to define the region that responds to the title bar behaviors. By default, the parts of any visual elements that are within the caption area of the window are not interactive. To enable interactive elements in the caption area, attach the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome%2A> attached property to the element and set it to `true`.","nodes":[{"content":"The area defined by the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A&gt;</ph> property starts at the bottom edge of the top resize border and extends downward the specified amount.","pos":[0,184],"source":"The area defined by the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property starts at the bottom edge of the top resize border and extends downward the specified amount."},{"content":"It spans the width of the window inside the right and left resize borders.","pos":[185,259]},{"content":"This area does not have any visual elements associated with it; it is only used to define the region that responds to the title bar behaviors.","pos":[260,402]},{"content":"By default, the parts of any visual elements that are within the caption area of the window are not interactive.","pos":[403,515]},{"content":"To enable interactive elements in the caption area, attach the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome%2A&gt;</ph> attached property to the element and set it to <ph id=\"ph2\">`true`</ph>.","pos":[516,702],"source":" To enable interactive elements in the caption area, attach the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome%2A> attached property to the element and set it to `true`."}]},{"pos":[1163,1194],"content":"Dependency Property Information","linkify":"Dependency Property Information","nodes":[{"content":"Dependency Property Information","pos":[0,31]}]},{"pos":[1215,1231],"content":"Identifier field","nodes":[{"content":"Identifier field","pos":[0,16]}]},{"pos":[1232,1294],"content":"<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeightProperty>","nodes":[]},{"pos":[1299,1332],"content":"Metadata properties set to <ph id=\"ph1\">`true`</ph>","source":"Metadata properties set to `true`"},{"pos":[1333,1337],"content":"None","nodes":[{"content":"None","pos":[0,4]}]}],"pos":[21040,22393],"yaml":true,"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"The height of the caption area.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,31],"content":"The height of the caption area.","nodes":[{"content":"The height of the caption area.","pos":[0,31]}]}],"pos":[22515,22547],"yaml":true},{"content":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\"></xref> dependency property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,104],"content":"Identifies the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> dependency property.","source":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\"></xref> dependency property."}],"pos":[23606,23711],"yaml":true},{"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates the amount that the corners of a window are rounded.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,88],"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates the amount that the corners of a window are rounded.","nodes":[{"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates the amount that the corners of a window are rounded.","pos":[0,88]}]}],"pos":[24819,24908],"yaml":true},{"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> property to specify the amount of rounding at the corners of a window. This property can be set to any non-negative double value. The values can be non-uniform.  \n  \n This property does not affect maximized windows or windows that have a Windows Aero glass frame. It only has an effect when Windows Aero (also called Desktop Window Manager) is not enabled or the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to 0. Hit testing in the non-client area does not take the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> into account when determining whether the mouse is over a resize border. If the radius is too large relative to the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> then it is possible that the user cannot perform a diagonal resize using the mouse.  \n  \n<a name=\"dependencyPropertyInfo_CornerRadius\"></a>   \n## Dependency Property Information  \n  \n|||  \n|-|-|  \n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadiusProperty>|  \n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|","nodes":[{"pos":[0,225],"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> property to specify the amount of rounding at the corners of a window. This property can be set to any non-negative double value. The values can be non-uniform.","nodes":[{"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> property to specify the amount of rounding at the corners of a window. This property can be set to any non-negative double value. The values can be non-uniform.","pos":[0,225],"nodes":[{"content":"Set the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A&gt;</ph> property to specify the amount of rounding at the corners of a window.","pos":[0,135],"source":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> property to specify the amount of rounding at the corners of a window."},{"content":"This property can be set to any non-negative double value.","pos":[136,194]},{"content":"The values can be non-uniform.","pos":[195,225]}]}]},{"pos":[232,889],"content":"This property does not affect maximized windows or windows that have a Windows Aero glass frame. It only has an effect when Windows Aero (also called Desktop Window Manager) is not enabled or the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to 0. Hit testing in the non-client area does not take the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> into account when determining whether the mouse is over a resize border. If the radius is too large relative to the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> then it is possible that the user cannot perform a diagonal resize using the mouse.","nodes":[{"content":"This property does not affect maximized windows or windows that have a Windows Aero glass frame. It only has an effect when Windows Aero (also called Desktop Window Manager) is not enabled or the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to 0. Hit testing in the non-client area does not take the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> into account when determining whether the mouse is over a resize border. If the radius is too large relative to the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> then it is possible that the user cannot perform a diagonal resize using the mouse.","pos":[0,657],"nodes":[{"content":"This property does not affect maximized windows or windows that have a Windows Aero glass frame.","pos":[0,96]},{"content":"It only has an effect when Windows Aero (also called Desktop Window Manager) is not enabled or the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property is set to 0.","pos":[97,281],"source":" It only has an effect when Windows Aero (also called Desktop Window Manager) is not enabled or the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to 0."},{"content":"Hit testing in the non-client area does not take the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A&gt;</ph> into account when determining whether the mouse is over a resize border.","pos":[282,464],"source":" Hit testing in the non-client area does not take the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> into account when determining whether the mouse is over a resize border."},{"content":"If the radius is too large relative to the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A&gt;</ph> then it is possible that the user cannot perform a diagonal resize using the mouse.","pos":[465,657],"source":" If the radius is too large relative to the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> then it is possible that the user cannot perform a diagonal resize using the mouse."}]}]},{"pos":[952,983],"content":"Dependency Property Information","linkify":"Dependency Property Information","nodes":[{"content":"Dependency Property Information","pos":[0,31]}]},{"pos":[1004,1020],"content":"Identifier field","nodes":[{"content":"Identifier field","pos":[0,16]}]},{"pos":[1021,1082],"content":"<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadiusProperty>","nodes":[]},{"pos":[1087,1120],"content":"Metadata properties set to <ph id=\"ph1\">`true`</ph>","source":"Metadata properties set to `true`"},{"pos":[1121,1125],"content":"None","nodes":[{"content":"None","pos":[0,4]}]}],"pos":[24919,26060],"yaml":true,"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"A value that describes the amount that corners are rounded.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,59],"content":"A value that describes the amount that corners are rounded.","nodes":[{"content":"A value that describes the amount that corners are rounded.","pos":[0,59]}]}],"pos":[26216,26276],"yaml":true},{"content":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius\"></xref> dependency property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,103],"content":"Identifies the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> dependency property.","source":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius\"></xref> dependency property."}],"pos":[27328,27432],"yaml":true},{"content":"Creates a new instance of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> class.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,91],"content":"Creates a new instance of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> class.","source":"Creates a new instance of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> class."}],"pos":[28579,28671],"yaml":true},{"content":"The new instance of this class.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,31],"content":"The new instance of this class.","nodes":[{"content":"The new instance of this class.","pos":[0,31]}]}],"pos":[28848,28880],"yaml":true},{"content":"Gets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property from the specified input element.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,153],"content":"Gets the value of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> attached property from the specified input element.","source":"Gets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property from the specified input element."}],"pos":[30116,30270],"yaml":true},{"content":"The input element from which to read the property value.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,56],"content":"The input element from which to read the property value.","nodes":[{"content":"The input element from which to read the property value.","pos":[0,56]}]}],"pos":[30484,30541],"yaml":true},{"content":"The value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,115],"content":"The value of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> attached property.","source":"The value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property."}],"pos":[30599,30715],"yaml":true},{"content":"<code>inputElement</code> is `null`.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,36],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;inputElement&lt;/code&gt;</ph> is <ph id=\"ph2\">`null`</ph>.","source":"<code>inputElement</code> is `null`."}],"pos":[30906,30943],"yaml":true},{"content":"<code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,88],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;inputElement&lt;/code&gt;</ph> is not a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph>.","source":"<code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>."}],"pos":[31037,31126],"yaml":true},{"content":"Gets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property from the specified input element.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,148],"content":"Gets the value of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> attached property from the specified input element.","source":"Gets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property from the specified input element."}],"pos":[32249,32398],"yaml":true},{"content":"The input element from which to read the property value.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,56],"content":"The input element from which to read the property value.","nodes":[{"content":"The input element from which to read the property value.","pos":[0,56]}]}],"pos":[32643,32700],"yaml":true},{"content":"The value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,110],"content":"The value of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> attached property.","source":"The value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property."}],"pos":[32784,32895],"yaml":true},{"content":"<code>inputElement</code> is `null`.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,36],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;inputElement&lt;/code&gt;</ph> is <ph id=\"ph2\">`null`</ph>.","source":"<code>inputElement</code> is `null`."}],"pos":[33081,33118],"yaml":true},{"content":"<code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,88],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;inputElement&lt;/code&gt;</ph> is not a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph>.","source":"<code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>."}],"pos":[33212,33301],"yaml":true},{"content":"Gets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> attached property from the specified <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref>.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,170],"content":"Gets the value of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> attached property from the specified <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph>.","source":"Gets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> attached property from the specified <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref>."}],"pos":[34340,34511],"yaml":true},{"content":"The <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref> from which to read the property value.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,85],"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> from which to read the property value.","source":"The <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref> from which to read the property value."}],"pos":[34716,34802],"yaml":true},{"content":"The instance of <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> that is attached to the specified <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref>.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,148],"content":"The instance of <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> that is attached to the specified <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph>.","source":"The instance of <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> that is attached to the specified <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref>."}],"pos":[34879,35028],"yaml":true},{"content":"<code>window</code> is `null`.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,30],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;window&lt;/code&gt;</ph> is <ph id=\"ph2\">`null`</ph>.","source":"<code>window</code> is `null`."}],"pos":[35207,35238],"yaml":true},{"content":"Gets a uniform thickness of -1.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,31],"content":"Gets a uniform thickness of -1.","nodes":[{"content":"Gets a uniform thickness of -1.","pos":[0,31]}]}],"pos":[36236,36268],"yaml":true},{"content":"The <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property. You set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property equal to <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> to extend the glass frame over the entire window. If the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,629],"content":"The <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property. You set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property equal to <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> to extend the glass frame over the entire window. If the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>.","nodes":[{"content":"The <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property. You set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property equal to <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> to extend the glass frame over the entire window. If the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>.","pos":[0,629],"nodes":[{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property.","pos":[0,184],"source":"The <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property."},{"content":"You set the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property equal to <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A&gt;</ph> to extend the glass frame over the entire window.","pos":[185,400],"source":" You set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property equal to <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> to extend the glass frame over the entire window."},{"content":"If the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A&gt;</ph>.","pos":[401,629],"source":" If the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>."}]}]}],"pos":[36279,36909],"yaml":true,"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"A uniform thickness of -1 in all cases.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,39],"content":"A uniform thickness of -1 in all cases.","nodes":[{"content":"A uniform thickness of -1 in all cases.","pos":[0,39]}]}],"pos":[37076,37116],"yaml":true},{"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates the width of the glass border around a window.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,82],"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates the width of the glass border around a window.","nodes":[{"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates the width of the glass border around a window.","pos":[0,82]}]}],"pos":[38158,38241],"yaml":true},{"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to specify the amount that the Windows Aero glass frame extends into the client area of a window. By default, the glass frame will use system values to emulate the look of a standard window. If Windows Aero is enabled, then the standard caption buttons (Maximize, Minimize, Close) are enabled and interactive. To make a custom window that does not have a glass frame, set this thickness to a uniform value of 0. This will disable the standard caption buttons.  \n  \n To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a negative value on any side. If the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>. The <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property that extends the glass over the entire window.  \n  \n Windows Aero glass effects are not supported on all operating systems, and can be disabled on supported operating systems. If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property value. You should check the <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available. If glass effects are not available, you should provide an alternate window style that does not use the glass frame.  \n  \n<a name=\"dependencyPropertyInfo_GlassFrameThickness\"></a>   \n## Dependency Property Information  \n  \n|||  \n|-|-|  \n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThicknessProperty>|  \n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|","nodes":[{"pos":[0,540],"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to specify the amount that the Windows Aero glass frame extends into the client area of a window. By default, the glass frame will use system values to emulate the look of a standard window. If Windows Aero is enabled, then the standard caption buttons (Maximize, Minimize, Close) are enabled and interactive. To make a custom window that does not have a glass frame, set this thickness to a uniform value of 0. This will disable the standard caption buttons.","nodes":[{"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to specify the amount that the Windows Aero glass frame extends into the client area of a window. By default, the glass frame will use system values to emulate the look of a standard window. If Windows Aero is enabled, then the standard caption buttons (Maximize, Minimize, Close) are enabled and interactive. To make a custom window that does not have a glass frame, set this thickness to a uniform value of 0. This will disable the standard caption buttons.","pos":[0,540],"nodes":[{"content":"Set the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property to specify the amount that the Windows Aero glass frame extends into the client area of a window.","pos":[0,178],"source":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to specify the amount that the Windows Aero glass frame extends into the client area of a window."},{"content":"By default, the glass frame will use system values to emulate the look of a standard window.","pos":[179,271]},{"content":"If Windows Aero is enabled, then the standard caption buttons (Maximize, Minimize, Close) are enabled and interactive.","pos":[272,390]},{"content":"To make a custom window that does not have a glass frame, set this thickness to a uniform value of 0.","pos":[391,492]},{"content":"This will disable the standard caption buttons.","pos":[493,540]}]}]},{"pos":[547,1173],"content":"To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a negative value on any side. If the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>. The <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property that extends the glass over the entire window.","nodes":[{"content":"To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a negative value on any side. If the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>. The <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property that extends the glass over the entire window.","pos":[0,626],"nodes":[{"content":"To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property to a negative value on any side.","pos":[0,167],"source":"To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a negative value on any side."},{"content":"If the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to<ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A&gt;</ph>.","pos":[168,395],"source":" If the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>."},{"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property that extends the glass over the entire window.","pos":[396,626],"source":" The <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property that extends the glass over the entire window."}]}]},{"pos":[1180,1732],"content":"Windows Aero glass effects are not supported on all operating systems, and can be disabled on supported operating systems. If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property value. You should check the <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available. If glass effects are not available, you should provide an alternate window style that does not use the glass frame.","nodes":[{"content":"Windows Aero glass effects are not supported on all operating systems, and can be disabled on supported operating systems. If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property value. You should check the <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available. If glass effects are not available, you should provide an alternate window style that does not use the glass frame.","pos":[0,552],"nodes":[{"content":"Windows Aero glass effects are not supported on all operating systems, and can be disabled on supported operating systems.","pos":[0,122]},{"content":"If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property value.","pos":[123,292],"source":" If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property value."},{"content":"You should check the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A&gt;</ph> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available.","pos":[293,436],"source":" You should check the <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available."},{"content":"If glass effects are not available, you should provide an alternate window style that does not use the glass frame.","pos":[437,552]}]}]},{"pos":[1802,1833],"content":"Dependency Property Information","linkify":"Dependency Property Information","nodes":[{"content":"Dependency Property Information","pos":[0,31]}]},{"pos":[1854,1870],"content":"Identifier field","nodes":[{"content":"Identifier field","pos":[0,16]}]},{"pos":[1871,1939],"content":"<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThicknessProperty>","nodes":[]},{"pos":[1944,1977],"content":"Metadata properties set to <ph id=\"ph1\">`true`</ph>","source":"Metadata properties set to `true`"},{"pos":[1978,1982],"content":"None","nodes":[{"content":"None","pos":[0,4]}]}],"pos":[38252,40252],"yaml":true,"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"The width of the glass border around a window.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,46],"content":"The width of the glass border around a window.","nodes":[{"content":"The width of the glass border around a window.","pos":[0,46]}]}],"pos":[40409,40456],"yaml":true},{"content":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\"></xref> dependency property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,110],"content":"Identifies the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> dependency property.","source":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\"></xref> dependency property."}],"pos":[41535,41646],"yaml":true},{"content":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> dependency property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,115],"content":"Identifies the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> dependency property.","source":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> dependency property."}],"pos":[42899,43015],"yaml":true},{"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates which edges of the window frame are not owned by the client.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,96],"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates which edges of the window frame are not owned by the client.","nodes":[{"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates which edges of the window frame are not owned by the client.","pos":[0,96]}]}],"pos":[44198,44295],"yaml":true},{"content":"<a name=\"dependencyPropertyInfo_NonClientFrameEdges\"></a>   \n## Dependency Property Information  \n  \n|||  \n|-|-|  \n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdgesProperty>|  \n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|","nodes":[{"pos":[64,95],"content":"Dependency Property Information","linkify":"Dependency Property Information","nodes":[{"content":"Dependency Property Information","pos":[0,31]}]},{"pos":[116,132],"content":"Identifier field","nodes":[{"content":"Identifier field","pos":[0,16]}]},{"pos":[133,201],"content":"<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdgesProperty>","nodes":[]},{"pos":[206,239],"content":"Metadata properties set to <ph id=\"ph1\">`true`</ph>","source":"Metadata properties set to `true`"},{"pos":[240,244],"content":"None","nodes":[{"content":"None","pos":[0,4]}]}],"pos":[44306,44562],"yaml":true,"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"A bitwise combination of the enumeration values that specify which edges of the frame are not owned by the client.  \n  \n The registered default is <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.NonClientFrameEdges.None\"></xref>. For more information about what can influence the value, see [Dependency Property Value Precedence](~/docs/framework/wpf/advanced/dependency-property-value-precedence.md).","nodes":[{"pos":[0,114],"content":"A bitwise combination of the enumeration values that specify which edges of the frame are not owned by the client.","nodes":[{"content":"A bitwise combination of the enumeration values that specify which edges of the frame are not owned by the client.","pos":[0,114]}]},{"pos":[121,386],"content":"The registered default is <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.NonClientFrameEdges.None\"></xref>. For more information about what can influence the value, see [Dependency Property Value Precedence](~/docs/framework/wpf/advanced/dependency-property-value-precedence.md).","nodes":[{"content":"The registered default is <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.NonClientFrameEdges.None\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph>.","pos":[0,93],"source":"The registered default is <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.NonClientFrameEdges.None\"></xref>."},{"content":"For more information about what can influence the value, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dependency Property Value Precedence<ept id=\"p1\">](~/docs/framework/wpf/advanced/dependency-property-value-precedence.md)</ept>.","pos":[94,265],"source":" For more information about what can influence the value, see [Dependency Property Value Precedence](~/docs/framework/wpf/advanced/dependency-property-value-precedence.md)."}]}],"pos":[44751,45144],"yaml":true},{"content":"‘Left, Right, Top, Bottom’ is not a valid value. At least one edge must belong to the client.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,93],"content":"‘Left, Right, Top, Bottom’ is not a valid value. At least one edge must belong to the client.","nodes":[{"content":"‘Left, Right, Top, Bottom’ is not a valid value. At least one edge must belong to the client.","pos":[0,93],"nodes":[{"content":"‘Left, Right, Top, Bottom’ is not a valid value.","pos":[0,48]},{"content":"At least one edge must belong to the client.","pos":[49,93]}]}]}],"pos":[45319,45413],"yaml":true},{"content":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\"></xref> dependency property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,110],"content":"Identifies the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> dependency property.","source":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\"></xref> dependency property."}],"pos":[46430,46541],"yaml":true},{"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates the width of the border that is used to resize a window.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,92],"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates the width of the border that is used to resize a window.","nodes":[{"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates the width of the border that is used to resize a window.","pos":[0,92]}]}],"pos":[47731,47824],"yaml":true},{"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> property to specify the width of the area where a user can click-and-drag to resize a window. The mouse pointer changes to resize arrows when it is moved over the resize border.  \n  \n This property can be set to any non-negative double value. The values can be non-uniform. By default, the resize border will use system values to emulate the behavior of a standard window.  \n  \n This area is only used to define the region that is used to resize the window; it does not have any visual elements associated with it. However, it does affect the layout of elements inside the resize border.  \n  \n<a name=\"dependencyPropertyInfo_ResizeBorderThickness\"></a>   \n## Dependency Property Information  \n  \n|||  \n|-|-|  \n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThicknessProperty>|  \n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|","nodes":[{"pos":[0,251],"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> property to specify the width of the area where a user can click-and-drag to resize a window. The mouse pointer changes to resize arrows when it is moved over the resize border.","nodes":[{"content":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> property to specify the width of the area where a user can click-and-drag to resize a window. The mouse pointer changes to resize arrows when it is moved over the resize border.","pos":[0,251],"nodes":[{"content":"Set the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A&gt;</ph> property to specify the width of the area where a user can click-and-drag to resize a window.","pos":[0,167],"source":"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> property to specify the width of the area where a user can click-and-drag to resize a window."},{"content":"The mouse pointer changes to resize arrows when it is moved over the resize border.","pos":[168,251]}]}]},{"pos":[258,446],"content":"This property can be set to any non-negative double value. The values can be non-uniform. By default, the resize border will use system values to emulate the behavior of a standard window.","nodes":[{"content":"This property can be set to any non-negative double value. The values can be non-uniform. By default, the resize border will use system values to emulate the behavior of a standard window.","pos":[0,188],"nodes":[{"content":"This property can be set to any non-negative double value.","pos":[0,58]},{"content":"The values can be non-uniform.","pos":[59,89]},{"content":"By default, the resize border will use system values to emulate the behavior of a standard window.","pos":[90,188]}]}]},{"pos":[453,661],"content":"This area is only used to define the region that is used to resize the window; it does not have any visual elements associated with it. However, it does affect the layout of elements inside the resize border.","nodes":[{"content":"This area is only used to define the region that is used to resize the window; it does not have any visual elements associated with it. However, it does affect the layout of elements inside the resize border.","pos":[0,208],"nodes":[{"content":"This area is only used to define the region that is used to resize the window; it does not have any visual elements associated with it.","pos":[0,135]},{"content":"However, it does affect the layout of elements inside the resize border.","pos":[136,208]}]}]},{"pos":[733,764],"content":"Dependency Property Information","linkify":"Dependency Property Information","nodes":[{"content":"Dependency Property Information","pos":[0,31]}]},{"pos":[785,801],"content":"Identifier field","nodes":[{"content":"Identifier field","pos":[0,16]}]},{"pos":[802,872],"content":"<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThicknessProperty>","nodes":[]},{"pos":[877,910],"content":"Metadata properties set to <ph id=\"ph1\">`true`</ph>","source":"Metadata properties set to `true`"},{"pos":[911,915],"content":"None","nodes":[{"content":"None","pos":[0,4]}]}],"pos":[47835,48768],"yaml":true,"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"The width of the border that is used to resize a window.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,56],"content":"The width of the border that is used to resize a window.","nodes":[{"content":"The width of the border that is used to resize a window.","pos":[0,56]}]}],"pos":[48927,48984],"yaml":true},{"content":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\"></xref> dependency property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,112],"content":"Identifies the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> dependency property.","source":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\"></xref> dependency property."}],"pos":[50077,50190],"yaml":true},{"content":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> dependency property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,110],"content":"Identifies the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> dependency property.","source":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> dependency property."}],"pos":[51415,51526],"yaml":true},{"content":"Sets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property on the specified input element.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,151],"content":"Sets the value of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> attached property on the specified input element.","source":"Sets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property on the specified input element."}],"pos":[52957,53109],"yaml":true},{"content":"The element on which to set the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,130],"content":"The element on which to set the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> attached property.","source":"The element on which to set the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property."}],"pos":[53344,53475],"yaml":true},{"content":"The property value to set.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,26],"content":"The property value to set.","nodes":[{"content":"The property value to set.","pos":[0,26]}]}],"pos":[53546,53573],"yaml":true},{"content":"<code>inputElement</code> is `null`.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,36],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;inputElement&lt;/code&gt;</ph> is <ph id=\"ph2\">`null`</ph>.","source":"<code>inputElement</code> is `null`."}],"pos":[53764,53801],"yaml":true},{"content":"<code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,88],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;inputElement&lt;/code&gt;</ph> is not a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph>.","source":"<code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>."}],"pos":[53895,53984],"yaml":true},{"content":"Sets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property on the specified input element.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,146],"content":"Sets the value of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> attached property on the specified input element.","source":"Sets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property on the specified input element."}],"pos":[55293,55440],"yaml":true},{"content":"The element on which to set the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,125],"content":"The element on which to set the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> attached property.","source":"The element on which to set the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property."}],"pos":[55701,55827],"yaml":true},{"content":"The property value to set.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,26],"content":"The property value to set.","nodes":[{"content":"The property value to set.","pos":[0,26]}]}],"pos":[55919,55946],"yaml":true},{"content":"<code>inputElement</code> is `null`.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,36],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;inputElement&lt;/code&gt;</ph> is <ph id=\"ph2\">`null`</ph>.","source":"<code>inputElement</code> is `null`."}],"pos":[56132,56169],"yaml":true},{"content":"<code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,88],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;inputElement&lt;/code&gt;</ph> is not a <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph>.","source":"<code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>."}],"pos":[56263,56352],"yaml":true},{"content":"Sets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> attached property on the specified <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref>.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,168],"content":"Sets the value of the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> attached property on the specified <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph>.","source":"Sets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> attached property on the specified <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref>."}],"pos":[57535,57704],"yaml":true},{"content":"The <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref> on which to set the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> attached property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,153],"content":"The <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> on which to set the <ph id=\"ph2\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> attached property.","source":"The <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref> on which to set the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> attached property."}],"pos":[57922,58076],"yaml":true},{"content":"The instance of <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> to set.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,78],"content":"The instance of <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> to set.","source":"The instance of <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> to set."}],"pos":[58158,58237],"yaml":true},{"content":"<code>window</code> is `null`.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,30],"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;code&gt;window&lt;/code&gt;</ph> is <ph id=\"ph2\">`null`</ph>.","source":"<code>window</code> is `null`."}],"pos":[58416,58447],"yaml":true},{"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates whether hit-testing is enabled on the Windows Aero caption buttons.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,103],"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates whether hit-testing is enabled on the Windows Aero caption buttons.","nodes":[{"content":"Gets or sets a value that indicates whether hit-testing is enabled on the Windows Aero caption buttons.","pos":[0,103]}]}],"pos":[59431,59535],"yaml":true},{"content":"The default Windows Aero caption buttons are Close, Maximize/Restore, and Minimize. If you do not use the Windows Aero captions buttons, you should provide an alternative method for a user to accomplish these tasks.  \n  \n<a name=\"dependencyPropertyInfo_UseAeroCaptionButtons\"></a>   \n## Dependency Property Information  \n  \n|||  \n|-|-|  \n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty>|  \n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|","nodes":[{"pos":[0,215],"content":"The default Windows Aero caption buttons are Close, Maximize/Restore, and Minimize. If you do not use the Windows Aero captions buttons, you should provide an alternative method for a user to accomplish these tasks.","nodes":[{"content":"The default Windows Aero caption buttons are Close, Maximize/Restore, and Minimize. If you do not use the Windows Aero captions buttons, you should provide an alternative method for a user to accomplish these tasks.","pos":[0,215],"nodes":[{"content":"The default Windows Aero caption buttons are Close, Maximize/Restore, and Minimize.","pos":[0,83]},{"content":"If you do not use the Windows Aero captions buttons, you should provide an alternative method for a user to accomplish these tasks.","pos":[84,215]}]}]},{"pos":[287,318],"content":"Dependency Property Information","linkify":"Dependency Property Information","nodes":[{"content":"Dependency Property Information","pos":[0,31]}]},{"pos":[339,355],"content":"Identifier field","nodes":[{"content":"Identifier field","pos":[0,16]}]},{"pos":[356,426],"content":"<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty>","nodes":[]},{"pos":[431,464],"content":"Metadata properties set to <ph id=\"ph1\">`true`</ph>","source":"Metadata properties set to `true`"},{"pos":[465,469],"content":"None","nodes":[{"content":"None","pos":[0,4]}]}],"pos":[59546,60029],"yaml":true,"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"`true` if hit-testing is enabled on the caption buttons; otherwise, `false`. The registered default is `true`. For more information about what can influence the value, see [Dependency Property Value Precedence](~/docs/framework/wpf/advanced/dependency-property-value-precedence.md).","nodes":[{"pos":[0,282],"content":"`true` if hit-testing is enabled on the caption buttons; otherwise, `false`. The registered default is `true`. For more information about what can influence the value, see [Dependency Property Value Precedence](~/docs/framework/wpf/advanced/dependency-property-value-precedence.md).","nodes":[{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">`true`</ph> if hit-testing is enabled on the caption buttons; otherwise, <ph id=\"ph2\">`false`</ph>.","pos":[0,76],"source":"`true` if hit-testing is enabled on the caption buttons; otherwise, `false`."},{"content":"The registered default is <ph id=\"ph1\">`true`</ph>.","pos":[77,110],"source":" The registered default is `true`."},{"content":"For more information about what can influence the value, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dependency Property Value Precedence<ept id=\"p1\">](~/docs/framework/wpf/advanced/dependency-property-value-precedence.md)</ept>.","pos":[111,282],"source":" For more information about what can influence the value, see [Dependency Property Value Precedence](~/docs/framework/wpf/advanced/dependency-property-value-precedence.md)."}]}],"pos":[60158,60443],"yaml":true},{"content":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\"></xref> dependency property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,112],"content":"Identifies the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> dependency property.","source":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\"></xref> dependency property."}],"pos":[61558,61671],"yaml":true},{"content":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> dependency property.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,103],"content":"Identifies the <ph id=\"ph1\">&lt;xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;</ph> dependency property.","source":"Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> dependency property."}],"pos":[62854,62958],"yaml":true}],"content":"### YamlMime:ManagedReference\nitems:\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  commentId: T:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  id: WindowChrome\n  children:\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.#ctor\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeightProperty\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadiusProperty\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(System.Windows.IInputElement)\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection(System.Windows.IInputElement)\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome(System.Windows.Window)\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThicknessProperty\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdgesProperty\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThicknessProperty\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirectionProperty\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(System.Windows.IInputElement,System.Boolean)\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection(System.Windows.IInputElement,System.Windows.Shell.ResizeGripDirection)\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome(System.Windows.Window,System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome)\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty\n  - System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChromeProperty\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: WindowChrome\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome\n  fullName: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  type: Class\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Represents an object that describes the customizations to the non-client area of a window.\n  remarks: \"The                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class enables you to extend Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) content into the non-client area of a window that is typically reserved for the operating system’s window manager.  \\n  \\n## Standard Windows  \\n Standard windows are composed of two overlapping rectangles. The outer rectangle is the                                  *non-client area*, which is often referred to as                                  *chrome*. It is drawn and managed by the operating system’s window manager. Its dimensions are determined by standard operating system settings. The non-client frame provides standard window features and behaviors. These include caption buttons (Minimize, Maximize, and Close), the window border, resize and move behaviors, the application icon and title, and the system menu. The inner rectangle is the                                  *client area*. It contains the contents of your application, and it is drawn and managed by the application. For more information about windows in WPF applications, see                                  [WPF Windows Overview](~/docs/framework/wpf/app-development/wpf-windows-overview.md).  \\n  \\n The following illustration shows the parts of a standard window.  \\n  \\n ![Window elements](~/add/media/windowoverviewfigure1.PNG \\\"Window elements\\\")  \\n  \\n## Custom Windows  \\n You can customize a window border by setting the                                  <xref:System.Windows.Window.WindowStyle%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property to                                  <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle.None> or by using the                                  <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class.  \\n  \\n### WindowStyle.None  \\n One way to customize the appearance of a WPF application window is to set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Window.WindowStyle%2A?displayProperty=fullName> property to                                          <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle.None>. This removes the non-client frame from the window and leaves only the client area, to which you can apply a custom style. However, when the non-client frame is removed, you also lose the system features and behaviors that it provides, such as caption buttons and window resizing. Another side effect is that the window will cover the Windows taskbar when it is maximized. Setting                                          <xref:System.Windows.WindowStyle?displayProperty=fullName> enables you to create a completely custom application, but also requires that you implement custom logic in your application to emulate standard window behavior.  \\n  \\n### WindowChrome  \\n To customize a window while retaining its standard functionality, you can use the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class. The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class separates the functionality of the window frame from the visuals, and lets you control the boundary between the client and non-client areas of your application window. The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class lets you put WPF content in the window frame by extending the client area to cover the non-client area. At the same time, it retains system behaviors through two invisible areas; the                                          *resize border* and                                          *caption* areas                                         .  \\n  \\n There are                                          two main parts                                          to creating a custom window using the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> class. First, you customize the non-client part of the window by setting properties exposed on the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> object. Then you provide a template for the window that defines the part of your application that is extended into the non-client area.The properties exposed on the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome> object are                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A>,                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A>,                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A>, and                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A>.  \\n  \\n The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> property specifies an invisible border around the outside of the application window that the user can click-and-drag to resize the window.  \\n  \\n The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property specifies an invisible area at the top of the window that enables system behaviors typically associated with the title bar. These behaviors include: click and drag to move the window, double-click to maximize the window, and right-click to show the system menu.  \\n  \\n The resize border and caption area do not have any visual elements; they only define areas that respond to input and enable standard system-provided window behaviors.  \\n  \\n The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> property specifies the amount that the corners of the window are rounded. This property does not have any effect if the glass frame is enabled for a window.  \\n  \\n The                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property specifies the width of the glass frame around the window. By default, it uses the system value specified by the                                          <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.WindowNonClientFrameThickness%2A> property to emulate the appearance of a standard window. When the glass frame is used, the caption buttons for Minimize, Maximize, and Close are visible and interactive. The application is responsible for displaying the application icon and caption text. You can set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to make the glass frame wider or narrower than the default.  \\n  \\n> [!CAUTION]\\n>  The size of the caption buttons does not change when the                                              <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is changed. If the height of the top of the glass frame is less than the height of the caption buttons, the caption buttons will not be completely visible.  \\n  \\n To make a custom window that does not have a glass frame, set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a uniform value of 0. This will disable and hide the standard caption buttons.  \\n  \\n To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a negative value on any side. When the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>.  \\n  \\n> [!NOTE]\\n>  Aero is a set of visual enhancements to the look and functionality of the Windows desktop that was introduced in Windows Vista. One of the more visually obvious features of Aero is translucent glass window borders. Windows Aero is enabled by the desktop composition feature of the Desktop Window Manager (DWM).  \\n  \\n Windows Aero glass effects are not supported on all operating systems, and can be disabled on supported operating systems. If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the                                          <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property value. The border area specified by this property will appear black instead.Check the                                          <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available. If glass effects are not available, you should provide an alternate window style that does not use the glass frame or use the standard window by setting the window style to null.  \\n  \\n You extend your WPF content into the window frame by specifying a ControlTemplate that defines the appearance and behavior of the frame content. You set the TargetType of the ControlTemplate to the type of the window that you are customizing.  \\n  \\n```  \\n<ControlTemplate TargetType=\\\"{x:Type local:MainWindow}\\\">  \\n```  \\n  \\n By default, the parts of any visual elements that are within the non-client area of the window are not interactive. To enable interactive elements in the non-client area, attach the WindowsChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome attached property to the element and set it to true.  \\n  \\n The following XAML markup shows the main elements needed to customize a window using the WindowChrome class.  \\n  \\n```  \\n<Style x:Key=\\\"StandardStyle\\\" TargetType=\\\"{x:Type local:MainWindow}\\\">  \\n    <Setter Property=\\\"shell:WindowChrome.WindowChrome\\\">  \\n        <Setter.Value>  \\n            <shell:WindowChrome />  \\n        </Setter.Value>  \\n    </Setter>  \\n    <Setter Property=\\\"Template\\\">  \\n        <Setter.Value>  \\n            <ControlTemplate TargetType=\\\"{x:Type local:MainWindow}\\\">  \\n                <Grid>  \\n                    <Border Background=\\\"White\\\"  \\n                            Margin=\\\"{Binding Source={x:Static shell:SystemParameters2.Current}, Path=WindowNonClientFrameThickness}\\\">  \\n                        <ContentPresenter Content=\\\"{TemplateBinding Content}\\\" />  \\n                    </Border>  \\n                    <TextBlock Text=\\\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=Title}\\\"   \\n                               VerticalAlignment=\\\"Top\\\" HorizontalAlignment=\\\"Left\\\"   \\n                               Margin=\\\"36,8,0,0\\\"/>  \\n                    <Image Source=\\\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=Icon}\\\"  \\n                           VerticalAlignment=\\\"Top\\\" HorizontalAlignment=\\\"Left\\\"  \\n                           Margin=\\\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=(shell:WindowChrome.WindowChrome).ResizeBorderThickness}\\\"   \\n                           Width=\\\"{Binding Source={x:Static shell:SystemParameters2.Current}, Path=SmallIconSize.Width}\\\"  \\n                           shell:WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome=\\\"True\\\"/>  \\n                </Grid>  \\n            </ControlTemplate>  \\n        </Setter.Value>  \\n    </Setter>  \\n</Style>  \\n```  \\n  \\n The first setter attaches the WindowChrome to the window. It uses all default values for the WindowChrome properties, which makes the window look like a standard window.  \\n  \\n```  \\n<Setter Property=\\\"shell:WindowChrome.WindowChrome\\\">  \\n    <Setter.Value>  \\n        <shell:WindowChrome />  \\n    </Setter.Value>  \\n</Setter>  \\n```  \\n  \\n The window template must specify a content presenter to display the contents of the window specified in your application. By default the WindowChrome class extends the client area to cover the non-client border. In order to uncover the glass frame, you need to specify a margin around the ContentPresenter. This markup specifies a border with a white background around the content presenter to emulate the appearance of a standard window. It also specifies a margin that is bound to the WindowNonClientFrameThickness property, which gets the default system width for the frame.  \\n  \\n```  \\n<Border Background=\\\"White\\\"  \\n    Margin=\\\"{Binding Source={x:Static shell:SystemParameters2.Current}, Path=WindowNonClientFrameThickness}\\\">  \\n    <ContentPresenter Content=\\\"{TemplateBinding Content}\\\" />  \\n</Border>  \\n```  \\n  \\n The application icon and title are not displayed by the WindowChrome class; they have to be added to the border as custom content. The following XAML adds an image and a textblock to display the icon and title. Both elements are bound to the corresponding properties on the window. The image width is bound to the SmallIconSize width, which gets the default system size for the icon. The IsHitTestVisibleInChrome attached property is set on the image so that it can receive mouse events.  \\n  \\n```  \\n<Image Source=\\\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=Icon}\\\"  \\n       VerticalAlignment=\\\"Top\\\" HorizontalAlignment=\\\"Left\\\"  \\n       Margin=\\\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=(shell:WindowChrome.WindowChrome).ResizeBorderThickness}\\\"   \\n       Width=\\\"{Binding Source={x:Static shell:SystemParameters2.Current}, Path=SmallIconSize.Width}\\\"  \\n       shell:WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome=\\\"True\\\"/>  \\n  \\n<TextBlock Text=\\\"{Binding RelativeSource={RelativeSource TemplatedParent}, Path=Title}\\\"   \\n           VerticalAlignment=\\\"Top\\\" HorizontalAlignment=\\\"Left\\\"   \\n           Margin=\\\"36,8,0,0\\\"/>  \\n```\"\n  syntax:\n    content: 'public class WindowChrome : System.Windows.Freezable'\n  inheritance:\n  - System.Object\n  - System.Windows.Threading.DispatcherObject\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  - System.Windows.Freezable\n  implements: []\n  inheritedMembers:\n  - System.Object.Equals(System.Object,System.Object)\n  - System.Object.GetType\n  - System.Object.MemberwiseClone\n  - System.Object.ReferenceEquals(System.Object,System.Object)\n  - System.Object.ToString\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.ClearValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.ClearValue(System.Windows.DependencyPropertyKey)\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.CoerceValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.DependencyObjectType\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.Equals(System.Object)\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.GetHashCode\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.GetLocalValueEnumerator\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.GetValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.InvalidateProperty(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.IsSealed\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.ReadLocalValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.SetCurrentValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty,System.Object)\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.SetValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty,System.Object)\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.SetValue(System.Windows.DependencyPropertyKey,System.Object)\n  - System.Windows.DependencyObject.ShouldSerializeProperty(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.CanFreeze\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.Changed\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.Clone\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.CloneCore(System.Windows.Freezable)\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.CloneCurrentValue\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.CloneCurrentValueCore(System.Windows.Freezable)\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.CreateInstance\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.Freeze\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.Freeze(System.Windows.Freezable,System.Boolean)\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.FreezeCore(System.Boolean)\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.GetAsFrozen\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.GetAsFrozenCore(System.Windows.Freezable)\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.GetCurrentValueAsFrozen\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.GetCurrentValueAsFrozenCore(System.Windows.Freezable)\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.IsFrozen\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.OnChanged\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.OnFreezablePropertyChanged(System.Windows.DependencyObject,System.Windows.DependencyObject)\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.OnFreezablePropertyChanged(System.Windows.DependencyObject,System.Windows.DependencyObject,System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.OnPropertyChanged(System.Windows.DependencyPropertyChangedEventArgs)\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.ReadPreamble\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.WritePostscript\n  - System.Windows.Freezable.WritePreamble\n  - System.Windows.Threading.DispatcherObject.CheckAccess\n  - System.Windows.Threading.DispatcherObject.Dispatcher\n  - System.Windows.Threading.DispatcherObject.VerifyAccess\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.#ctor\n  commentId: M:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.#ctor\n  id: '#ctor'\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: WindowChrome()\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.WindowChrome()\n  fullName: WindowChrome.WindowChrome()\n  type: Constructor\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Initializes a new instance of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> class.\n  syntax:\n    content: public WindowChrome ();\n    parameters: []\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.#ctor*\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  ms.author: kempb\n  manager: ghogen\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\n  commentId: P:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\n  id: CaptionHeight\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: CaptionHeight\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\n  type: Property\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Gets or sets the height of the caption area at the top of a window.\n  remarks: \"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property to specify the area at the top of the window that enables the system behaviors typically associated with the title bar. These behaviors include double-click to maximize the window, right-click to open the system menu, and click-and-drag to move the window. This property can be set to any non-negative double value.  \\n  \\n The area defined by the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight%2A> property starts at the bottom edge of the top resize border and extends downward the specified amount. It spans the width of the window inside the right and left resize borders. This area does not have any visual elements associated with it; it is only used to define the region that responds to the title bar behaviors. By default, the parts of any visual elements that are within the caption area of the window are not interactive. To enable interactive elements in the caption area, attach the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome%2A> attached property to the element and set it to `true`.  \\n  \\n<a name=\\\"dependencyPropertyInfo_CaptionHeight\\\"></a>   \\n## Dependency Property Information  \\n  \\n|||  \\n|-|-|  \\n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeightProperty>|  \\n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|\"\n  syntax:\n    content: public double CaptionHeight { get; set; }\n    return:\n      type: System.Double\n      description: The height of the caption area.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight*\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeightProperty\n  commentId: F:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeightProperty\n  id: CaptionHeightProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: CaptionHeightProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CaptionHeightProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CaptionHeightProperty\n  type: Field\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\"></xref> dependency property.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static readonly System.Windows.DependencyProperty CaptionHeightProperty;\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.DependencyProperty\n      description: ''\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  ms.author: kempb\n  manager: ghogen\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius\n  commentId: P:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius\n  id: CornerRadius\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: CornerRadius\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CornerRadius\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CornerRadius\n  type: Property\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Gets or sets a value that indicates the amount that the corners of a window are rounded.\n  remarks: \"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> property to specify the amount of rounding at the corners of a window. This property can be set to any non-negative double value. The values can be non-uniform.  \\n  \\n This property does not affect maximized windows or windows that have a Windows Aero glass frame. It only has an effect when Windows Aero (also called Desktop Window Manager) is not enabled or the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to 0. Hit testing in the non-client area does not take the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius%2A> into account when determining whether the mouse is over a resize border. If the radius is too large relative to the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> then it is possible that the user cannot perform a diagonal resize using the mouse.  \\n  \\n<a name=\\\"dependencyPropertyInfo_CornerRadius\\\"></a>   \\n## Dependency Property Information  \\n  \\n|||  \\n|-|-|  \\n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadiusProperty>|  \\n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|\"\n  syntax:\n    content: public System.Windows.CornerRadius CornerRadius { get; set; }\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.CornerRadius\n      description: A value that describes the amount that corners are rounded.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius*\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadiusProperty\n  commentId: F:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadiusProperty\n  id: CornerRadiusProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: CornerRadiusProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CornerRadiusProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CornerRadiusProperty\n  type: Field\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius\"></xref> dependency property.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static readonly System.Windows.DependencyProperty CornerRadiusProperty;\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.DependencyProperty\n      description: ''\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  ms.author: kempb\n  manager: ghogen\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore\n  commentId: M:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore\n  id: CreateInstanceCore\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: CreateInstanceCore()\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore()\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore()\n  type: Method\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Creates a new instance of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> class.\n  syntax:\n    content: protected override System.Windows.Freezable CreateInstanceCore ();\n    parameters: []\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.Freezable\n      description: The new instance of this class.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore*\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(System.Windows.IInputElement)\n  commentId: M:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(System.Windows.IInputElement)\n  id: GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(System.Windows.IInputElement)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement)\n  type: Method\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Gets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property from the specified input element.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static bool GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome (System.Windows.IInputElement inputElement);\n    parameters:\n    - id: inputElement\n      type: System.Windows.IInputElement\n      description: The input element from which to read the property value.\n    return:\n      type: System.Boolean\n      description: The value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome*\n  exceptions:\n  - type: System.ArgumentNullException\n    commentId: T:System.ArgumentNullException\n    description: <code>inputElement</code> is `null`.\n  - type: System.ArgumentException\n    commentId: T:System.ArgumentException\n    description: <code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>.\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection(System.Windows.IInputElement)\n  commentId: M:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection(System.Windows.IInputElement)\n  id: GetResizeGripDirection(System.Windows.IInputElement)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: GetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement)\n  type: Method\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Gets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property from the specified input element.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static System.Windows.Shell.ResizeGripDirection GetResizeGripDirection (System.Windows.IInputElement inputElement);\n    parameters:\n    - id: inputElement\n      type: System.Windows.IInputElement\n      description: The input element from which to read the property value.\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.Shell.ResizeGripDirection\n      description: The value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection*\n  exceptions:\n  - type: System.ArgumentNullException\n    commentId: T:System.ArgumentNullException\n    description: <code>inputElement</code> is `null`.\n  - type: System.ArgumentException\n    commentId: T:System.ArgumentException\n    description: <code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>.\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome(System.Windows.Window)\n  commentId: M:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome(System.Windows.Window)\n  id: GetWindowChrome(System.Windows.Window)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: GetWindowChrome(Window)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome(Window)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome(Window)\n  type: Method\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Gets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> attached property from the specified <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref>.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome GetWindowChrome (System.Windows.Window window);\n    parameters:\n    - id: window\n      type: System.Windows.Window\n      description: The <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref> from which to read the property value.\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n      description: The instance of <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> that is attached to the specified <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref>.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome*\n  exceptions:\n  - type: System.ArgumentNullException\n    commentId: T:System.ArgumentNullException\n    description: <code>window</code> is `null`.\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  ms.author: kempb\n  manager: ghogen\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  commentId: P:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  id: GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  type: Property\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Gets a uniform thickness of -1.\n  remarks: The <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property. You set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property equal to <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> to extend the glass frame over the entire window. If the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static System.Windows.Thickness GlassFrameCompleteThickness { get; }\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.Thickness\n      description: A uniform thickness of -1 in all cases.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness*\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  ms.author: kempb\n  manager: ghogen\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\n  commentId: P:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\n  id: GlassFrameThickness\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: GlassFrameThickness\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\n  type: Property\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Gets or sets a value that indicates the width of the glass border around a window.\n  remarks: \"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to specify the amount that the Windows Aero glass frame extends into the client area of a window. By default, the glass frame will use system values to emulate the look of a standard window. If Windows Aero is enabled, then the standard caption buttons (Maximize, Minimize, Close) are enabled and interactive. To make a custom window that does not have a glass frame, set this thickness to a uniform value of 0. This will disable the standard caption buttons.  \\n  \\n To extend the glass frame to cover the entire window, set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property to a negative value on any side. If the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property is set to a negative value for any side, its coerced value will be equal to<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A>. The <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness%2A> property is provided as a utility to enable you to set the thickness of the glass frame to a named property that extends the glass over the entire window.  \\n  \\n Windows Aero glass effects are not supported on all operating systems, and can be disabled on supported operating systems. If Windows Aero is not available, the glass frame will not be displayed regardless of the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness%2A> property value. You should check the <xref:System.Windows.SystemParameters.IsGlassEnabled%2A> property to verify that Windows Aero glass effects are available. If glass effects are not available, you should provide an alternate window style that does not use the glass frame.  \\n  \\n<a name=\\\"dependencyPropertyInfo_GlassFrameThickness\\\"></a>   \\n## Dependency Property Information  \\n  \\n|||  \\n|-|-|  \\n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThicknessProperty>|  \\n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|\"\n  syntax:\n    content: public System.Windows.Thickness GlassFrameThickness { get; set; }\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.Thickness\n      description: The width of the glass border around a window.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness*\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  ms.author: kempb\n  manager: ghogen\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThicknessProperty\n  commentId: F:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThicknessProperty\n  id: GlassFrameThicknessProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: GlassFrameThicknessProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GlassFrameThicknessProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GlassFrameThicknessProperty\n  type: Field\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\"></xref> dependency property.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static readonly System.Windows.DependencyProperty GlassFrameThicknessProperty;\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.DependencyProperty\n      description: ''\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty\n  commentId: F:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty\n  id: IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty\n  type: Field\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> dependency property.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static readonly System.Windows.DependencyProperty IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty;\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.DependencyProperty\n      description: ''\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\n  commentId: P:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\n  id: NonClientFrameEdges\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: NonClientFrameEdges\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\n  fullName: WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\n  type: Property\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Gets or sets a value that indicates which edges of the window frame are not owned by the client.\n  remarks: \"<a name=\\\"dependencyPropertyInfo_NonClientFrameEdges\\\"></a>   \\n## Dependency Property Information  \\n  \\n|||  \\n|-|-|  \\n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdgesProperty>|  \\n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|\"\n  syntax:\n    content: public System.Windows.Shell.NonClientFrameEdges NonClientFrameEdges { get; set; }\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.Shell.NonClientFrameEdges\n      description: \"A bitwise combination of the enumeration values that specify which edges of the frame are not owned by the client.  \\n  \\n The registered default is <xref href=\\\"System.Windows.Shell.NonClientFrameEdges.None\\\"></xref>. For more information about what can influence the value, see [Dependency Property Value Precedence](~/docs/framework/wpf/advanced/dependency-property-value-precedence.md).\"\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges*\n  exceptions:\n  - type: System.ArgumentException\n    commentId: T:System.ArgumentException\n    description: ‘Left, Right, Top, Bottom’ is not a valid value. At least one edge must belong to the client.\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdgesProperty\n  commentId: F:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdgesProperty\n  id: NonClientFrameEdgesProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: NonClientFrameEdgesProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdgesProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdgesProperty\n  type: Field\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\"></xref> dependency property.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static readonly System.Windows.DependencyProperty NonClientFrameEdgesProperty;\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.DependencyProperty\n      description: ''\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\n  commentId: P:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\n  id: ResizeBorderThickness\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: ResizeBorderThickness\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\n  fullName: WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\n  type: Property\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Gets or sets a value that indicates the width of the border that is used to resize a window.\n  remarks: \"Set the <xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness%2A> property to specify the width of the area where a user can click-and-drag to resize a window. The mouse pointer changes to resize arrows when it is moved over the resize border.  \\n  \\n This property can be set to any non-negative double value. The values can be non-uniform. By default, the resize border will use system values to emulate the behavior of a standard window.  \\n  \\n This area is only used to define the region that is used to resize the window; it does not have any visual elements associated with it. However, it does affect the layout of elements inside the resize border.  \\n  \\n<a name=\\\"dependencyPropertyInfo_ResizeBorderThickness\\\"></a>   \\n## Dependency Property Information  \\n  \\n|||  \\n|-|-|  \\n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThicknessProperty>|  \\n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|\"\n  syntax:\n    content: public System.Windows.Thickness ResizeBorderThickness { get; set; }\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.Thickness\n      description: The width of the border that is used to resize a window.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness*\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  ms.author: kempb\n  manager: ghogen\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThicknessProperty\n  commentId: F:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThicknessProperty\n  id: ResizeBorderThicknessProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: ResizeBorderThicknessProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThicknessProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThicknessProperty\n  type: Field\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\"></xref> dependency property.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static readonly System.Windows.DependencyProperty ResizeBorderThicknessProperty;\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.DependencyProperty\n      description: ''\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirectionProperty\n  commentId: F:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirectionProperty\n  id: ResizeGripDirectionProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: ResizeGripDirectionProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirectionProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirectionProperty\n  type: Field\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> dependency property.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static readonly System.Windows.DependencyProperty ResizeGripDirectionProperty;\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.DependencyProperty\n      description: ''\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(System.Windows.IInputElement,System.Boolean)\n  commentId: M:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(System.Windows.IInputElement,System.Boolean)\n  id: SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(System.Windows.IInputElement,System.Boolean)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement, Boolean)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement, Boolean)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement, Boolean)\n  type: Method\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Sets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property on the specified input element.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static void SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome (System.Windows.IInputElement inputElement, bool hitTestVisible);\n    parameters:\n    - id: inputElement\n      type: System.Windows.IInputElement\n      description: The element on which to set the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChrome\"></xref> attached property.\n    - id: hitTestVisible\n      type: System.Boolean\n      description: The property value to set.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome*\n  exceptions:\n  - type: System.ArgumentNullException\n    commentId: T:System.ArgumentNullException\n    description: <code>inputElement</code> is `null`.\n  - type: System.ArgumentException\n    commentId: T:System.ArgumentException\n    description: <code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>.\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection(System.Windows.IInputElement,System.Windows.Shell.ResizeGripDirection)\n  commentId: M:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection(System.Windows.IInputElement,System.Windows.Shell.ResizeGripDirection)\n  id: SetResizeGripDirection(System.Windows.IInputElement,System.Windows.Shell.ResizeGripDirection)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: SetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement, ResizeGripDirection)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement, ResizeGripDirection)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement, ResizeGripDirection)\n  type: Method\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Sets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property on the specified input element.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static void SetResizeGripDirection (System.Windows.IInputElement inputElement, System.Windows.Shell.ResizeGripDirection direction);\n    parameters:\n    - id: inputElement\n      type: System.Windows.IInputElement\n      description: The element on which to set the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirection\"></xref> attached property.\n    - id: direction\n      type: System.Windows.Shell.ResizeGripDirection\n      description: The property value to set.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection*\n  exceptions:\n  - type: System.ArgumentNullException\n    commentId: T:System.ArgumentNullException\n    description: <code>inputElement</code> is `null`.\n  - type: System.ArgumentException\n    commentId: T:System.ArgumentException\n    description: <code>inputElement</code> is not a <xref href=\"System.Windows.DependencyObject\"></xref>.\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome(System.Windows.Window,System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome)\n  commentId: M:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome(System.Windows.Window,System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome)\n  id: SetWindowChrome(System.Windows.Window,System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: SetWindowChrome(Window, WindowChrome)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome(Window, WindowChrome)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome(Window, WindowChrome)\n  type: Method\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Sets the value of the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> attached property on the specified <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref>.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static void SetWindowChrome (System.Windows.Window window, System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome chrome);\n    parameters:\n    - id: window\n      type: System.Windows.Window\n      description: The <xref href=\"System.Windows.Window\"></xref> on which to set the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> attached property.\n    - id: chrome\n      type: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n      description: The instance of <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\"></xref> to set.\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome*\n  exceptions:\n  - type: System.ArgumentNullException\n    commentId: T:System.ArgumentNullException\n    description: <code>window</code> is `null`.\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  commentId: P:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  id: UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  fullName: WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  type: Property\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Gets or sets a value that indicates whether hit-testing is enabled on the Windows Aero caption buttons.\n  remarks: \"The default Windows Aero caption buttons are Close, Maximize/Restore, and Minimize. If you do not use the Windows Aero captions buttons, you should provide an alternative method for a user to accomplish these tasks.  \\n  \\n<a name=\\\"dependencyPropertyInfo_UseAeroCaptionButtons\\\"></a>   \\n## Dependency Property Information  \\n  \\n|||  \\n|-|-|  \\n|Identifier field|<xref:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty>|  \\n|Metadata properties set to `true`|None|\"\n  syntax:\n    content: public bool UseAeroCaptionButtons { get; set; }\n    return:\n      type: System.Boolean\n      description: '`true` if hit-testing is enabled on the caption buttons; otherwise, `false`. The registered default is `true`. For more information about what can influence the value, see [Dependency Property Value Precedence](~/docs/framework/wpf/advanced/dependency-property-value-precedence.md).'\n  overload: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons*\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty\n  commentId: F:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty\n  id: UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty\n  type: Field\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\"></xref> dependency property.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static readonly System.Windows.DependencyProperty UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty;\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.DependencyProperty\n      description: ''\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChromeProperty\n  commentId: F:System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChromeProperty\n  id: WindowChromeProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  langs:\n  - csharp\n  name: WindowChromeProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.WindowChromeProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.WindowChromeProperty\n  type: Field\n  assemblies:\n  - PresentationFramework\n  namespace: System.Windows.Shell\n  summary: Identifies the <xref href=\"System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChrome\"></xref> dependency property.\n  syntax:\n    content: public static readonly System.Windows.DependencyProperty WindowChromeProperty;\n    return:\n      type: System.Windows.DependencyProperty\n      description: ''\n  exceptions: []\n  version:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n  ms.technology:\n  - dotnet-wpf\n  author: stevehoag\n  ms.author: shoag\n  manager: wpickett\nreferences:\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable\n  parent: System.Windows\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Freezable\n  nameWithType: Freezable\n  fullName: System.Windows.Freezable\n- uid: System.ArgumentNullException\n  parent: System\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ArgumentNullException\n  nameWithType: ArgumentNullException\n  fullName: System.ArgumentNullException\n- uid: System.ArgumentException\n  parent: System\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ArgumentException\n  nameWithType: ArgumentException\n  fullName: System.ArgumentException\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.#ctor\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: WindowChrome()\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.WindowChrome()\n  fullName: WindowChrome.WindowChrome()\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CaptionHeight\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\n- uid: System.Double\n  parent: System\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Double\n  nameWithType: Double\n  fullName: System.Double\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeightProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CaptionHeightProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CaptionHeightProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CaptionHeightProperty\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyProperty\n  parent: System.Windows\n  isExternal: false\n  name: DependencyProperty\n  nameWithType: DependencyProperty\n  fullName: System.Windows.DependencyProperty\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CornerRadius\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CornerRadius\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CornerRadius\n- uid: System.Windows.CornerRadius\n  parent: System.Windows\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CornerRadius\n  nameWithType: CornerRadius\n  fullName: System.Windows.CornerRadius\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadiusProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CornerRadiusProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CornerRadiusProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CornerRadiusProperty\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CreateInstanceCore()\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore()\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore()\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(System.Windows.IInputElement)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement)\n- uid: System.Boolean\n  parent: System\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Boolean\n  nameWithType: Boolean\n  fullName: System.Boolean\n- uid: System.Windows.IInputElement\n  parent: System.Windows\n  isExternal: false\n  name: IInputElement\n  nameWithType: IInputElement\n  fullName: System.Windows.IInputElement\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection(System.Windows.IInputElement)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement)\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.ResizeGripDirection\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ResizeGripDirection\n  nameWithType: ResizeGripDirection\n  fullName: System.Windows.Shell.ResizeGripDirection\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome(System.Windows.Window)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetWindowChrome(Window)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome(Window)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome(Window)\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell\n  isExternal: false\n  name: WindowChrome\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome\n  fullName: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n- uid: System.Windows.Window\n  parent: System.Windows\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Window\n  nameWithType: Window\n  fullName: System.Windows.Window\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n- uid: System.Windows.Thickness\n  parent: System.Windows\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Thickness\n  nameWithType: Thickness\n  fullName: System.Windows.Thickness\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GlassFrameThickness\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThicknessProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GlassFrameThicknessProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GlassFrameThicknessProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GlassFrameThicknessProperty\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.IsHitTestVisibleInChromeProperty\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: NonClientFrameEdges\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\n  fullName: WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.NonClientFrameEdges\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell\n  isExternal: false\n  name: NonClientFrameEdges\n  nameWithType: NonClientFrameEdges\n  fullName: System.Windows.Shell.NonClientFrameEdges\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdgesProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: NonClientFrameEdgesProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdgesProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdgesProperty\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ResizeBorderThickness\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\n  fullName: WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThicknessProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ResizeBorderThicknessProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThicknessProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThicknessProperty\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirectionProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ResizeGripDirectionProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirectionProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.ResizeGripDirectionProperty\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(System.Windows.IInputElement,System.Boolean)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement, Boolean)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement, Boolean)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome(IInputElement, Boolean)\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection(System.Windows.IInputElement,System.Windows.Shell.ResizeGripDirection)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: SetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement, ResizeGripDirection)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement, ResizeGripDirection)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection(IInputElement, ResizeGripDirection)\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome(System.Windows.Window,System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome)\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: SetWindowChrome(Window, WindowChrome)\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome(Window, WindowChrome)\n  fullName: WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome(Window, WindowChrome)\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  fullName: WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtonsProperty\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.WindowChromeProperty\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: WindowChromeProperty\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.WindowChromeProperty\n  fullName: WindowChrome.WindowChromeProperty\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.#ctor*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: WindowChrome\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.WindowChrome\n  fullName: WindowChrome.WindowChrome\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CaptionHeight*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CaptionHeight\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CaptionHeight\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CornerRadius*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CornerRadius\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CornerRadius\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CornerRadius\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CreateInstanceCore\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore\n  fullName: WindowChrome.CreateInstanceCore\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetResizeGripDirection\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GetResizeGripDirection\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetWindowChrome\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GetWindowChrome\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GlassFrameCompleteThickness\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GlassFrameThickness\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\n  fullName: WindowChrome.GlassFrameThickness\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: NonClientFrameEdges\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\n  fullName: WindowChrome.NonClientFrameEdges\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ResizeBorderThickness\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\n  fullName: WindowChrome.ResizeBorderThickness\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome\n  fullName: WindowChrome.SetIsHitTestVisibleInChrome\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: SetResizeGripDirection\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection\n  fullName: WindowChrome.SetResizeGripDirection\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: SetWindowChrome\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome\n  fullName: WindowChrome.SetWindowChrome\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons*\n  parent: System.Windows.Shell.WindowChrome\n  isExternal: false\n  name: UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  nameWithType: WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  fullName: WindowChrome.UseAeroCaptionButtons\n  monikers:\n  - netframework-4.5.1\n  - netframework-4.5.2\n  - netframework-4.5\n  - netframework-4.6.1\n  - netframework-4.6.2\n  - netframework-4.6\n  - netframework-4.7\n  content_git_url: https://github.com/dotnet/docs/blob/master/xml/System.Windows.Shell/WindowChrome.xml\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.Equals(System.Object)\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Equals(Object)\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.Equals(Object)\n  fullName: DependencyObject.Equals(Object)\n- uid: System.Object.Equals(System.Object,System.Object)\n  parent: System.Object\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Equals(Object, Object)\n  nameWithType: Object.Equals(Object, Object)\n  fullName: Object.Equals(Object, Object)\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.GetHashCode\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetHashCode()\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.GetHashCode()\n  fullName: DependencyObject.GetHashCode()\n- uid: System.Object.GetType\n  parent: System.Object\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetType()\n  nameWithType: Object.GetType()\n  fullName: Object.GetType()\n- uid: System.Object.MemberwiseClone\n  parent: System.Object\n  isExternal: false\n  name: MemberwiseClone()\n  nameWithType: Object.MemberwiseClone()\n  fullName: Object.MemberwiseClone()\n- uid: System.Object.ReferenceEquals(System.Object,System.Object)\n  parent: System.Object\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ReferenceEquals(Object, Object)\n  nameWithType: Object.ReferenceEquals(Object, Object)\n  fullName: Object.ReferenceEquals(Object, Object)\n- uid: System.Object.ToString\n  parent: System.Object\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ToString()\n  nameWithType: Object.ToString()\n  fullName: Object.ToString()\n- uid: System.Windows.Threading.DispatcherObject.CheckAccess\n  parent: System.Windows.Threading.DispatcherObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CheckAccess()\n  nameWithType: DispatcherObject.CheckAccess()\n  fullName: DispatcherObject.CheckAccess()\n- uid: System.Windows.Threading.DispatcherObject.Dispatcher\n  parent: System.Windows.Threading.DispatcherObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Dispatcher\n  nameWithType: DispatcherObject.Dispatcher\n  fullName: DispatcherObject.Dispatcher\n- uid: System.Windows.Threading.DispatcherObject.VerifyAccess\n  parent: System.Windows.Threading.DispatcherObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: VerifyAccess()\n  nameWithType: DispatcherObject.VerifyAccess()\n  fullName: DispatcherObject.VerifyAccess()\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.ClearValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ClearValue(DependencyProperty)\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.ClearValue(DependencyProperty)\n  fullName: DependencyObject.ClearValue(DependencyProperty)\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.ClearValue(System.Windows.DependencyPropertyKey)\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ClearValue(DependencyPropertyKey)\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.ClearValue(DependencyPropertyKey)\n  fullName: DependencyObject.ClearValue(DependencyPropertyKey)\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.CoerceValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CoerceValue(DependencyProperty)\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.CoerceValue(DependencyProperty)\n  fullName: DependencyObject.CoerceValue(DependencyProperty)\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.DependencyObjectType\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: DependencyObjectType\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.DependencyObjectType\n  fullName: DependencyObject.DependencyObjectType\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.GetLocalValueEnumerator\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetLocalValueEnumerator()\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.GetLocalValueEnumerator()\n  fullName: DependencyObject.GetLocalValueEnumerator()\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.GetValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetValue(DependencyProperty)\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.GetValue(DependencyProperty)\n  fullName: DependencyObject.GetValue(DependencyProperty)\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.InvalidateProperty(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: InvalidateProperty(DependencyProperty)\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.InvalidateProperty(DependencyProperty)\n  fullName: DependencyObject.InvalidateProperty(DependencyProperty)\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.IsSealed\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: IsSealed\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.IsSealed\n  fullName: DependencyObject.IsSealed\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.OnPropertyChanged(System.Windows.DependencyPropertyChangedEventArgs)\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: OnPropertyChanged(DependencyPropertyChangedEventArgs)\n  nameWithType: Freezable.OnPropertyChanged(DependencyPropertyChangedEventArgs)\n  fullName: Freezable.OnPropertyChanged(DependencyPropertyChangedEventArgs)\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.ReadLocalValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ReadLocalValue(DependencyProperty)\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.ReadLocalValue(DependencyProperty)\n  fullName: DependencyObject.ReadLocalValue(DependencyProperty)\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.SetCurrentValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty,System.Object)\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: SetCurrentValue(DependencyProperty, Object)\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.SetCurrentValue(DependencyProperty, Object)\n  fullName: DependencyObject.SetCurrentValue(DependencyProperty, Object)\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.SetValue(System.Windows.DependencyProperty,System.Object)\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: SetValue(DependencyProperty, Object)\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.SetValue(DependencyProperty, Object)\n  fullName: DependencyObject.SetValue(DependencyProperty, Object)\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.SetValue(System.Windows.DependencyPropertyKey,System.Object)\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: SetValue(DependencyPropertyKey, Object)\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.SetValue(DependencyPropertyKey, Object)\n  fullName: DependencyObject.SetValue(DependencyPropertyKey, Object)\n- uid: System.Windows.DependencyObject.ShouldSerializeProperty(System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  parent: System.Windows.DependencyObject\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ShouldSerializeProperty(DependencyProperty)\n  nameWithType: DependencyObject.ShouldSerializeProperty(DependencyProperty)\n  fullName: DependencyObject.ShouldSerializeProperty(DependencyProperty)\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.CanFreeze\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CanFreeze\n  nameWithType: Freezable.CanFreeze\n  fullName: Freezable.CanFreeze\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.Changed\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Changed\n  nameWithType: Freezable.Changed\n  fullName: Freezable.Changed\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.Clone\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Clone()\n  nameWithType: Freezable.Clone()\n  fullName: Freezable.Clone()\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.CloneCore(System.Windows.Freezable)\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CloneCore(Freezable)\n  nameWithType: Freezable.CloneCore(Freezable)\n  fullName: Freezable.CloneCore(Freezable)\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.CloneCurrentValue\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CloneCurrentValue()\n  nameWithType: Freezable.CloneCurrentValue()\n  fullName: Freezable.CloneCurrentValue()\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.CloneCurrentValueCore(System.Windows.Freezable)\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CloneCurrentValueCore(Freezable)\n  nameWithType: Freezable.CloneCurrentValueCore(Freezable)\n  fullName: Freezable.CloneCurrentValueCore(Freezable)\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.CreateInstance\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: CreateInstance()\n  nameWithType: Freezable.CreateInstance()\n  fullName: Freezable.CreateInstance()\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.Freeze\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Freeze()\n  nameWithType: Freezable.Freeze()\n  fullName: Freezable.Freeze()\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.Freeze(System.Windows.Freezable,System.Boolean)\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: Freeze(Freezable, Boolean)\n  nameWithType: Freezable.Freeze(Freezable, Boolean)\n  fullName: Freezable.Freeze(Freezable, Boolean)\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.FreezeCore(System.Boolean)\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: FreezeCore(Boolean)\n  nameWithType: Freezable.FreezeCore(Boolean)\n  fullName: Freezable.FreezeCore(Boolean)\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.GetAsFrozen\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetAsFrozen()\n  nameWithType: Freezable.GetAsFrozen()\n  fullName: Freezable.GetAsFrozen()\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.GetAsFrozenCore(System.Windows.Freezable)\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetAsFrozenCore(Freezable)\n  nameWithType: Freezable.GetAsFrozenCore(Freezable)\n  fullName: Freezable.GetAsFrozenCore(Freezable)\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.GetCurrentValueAsFrozen\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetCurrentValueAsFrozen()\n  nameWithType: Freezable.GetCurrentValueAsFrozen()\n  fullName: Freezable.GetCurrentValueAsFrozen()\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.GetCurrentValueAsFrozenCore(System.Windows.Freezable)\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: GetCurrentValueAsFrozenCore(Freezable)\n  nameWithType: Freezable.GetCurrentValueAsFrozenCore(Freezable)\n  fullName: Freezable.GetCurrentValueAsFrozenCore(Freezable)\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.IsFrozen\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: IsFrozen\n  nameWithType: Freezable.IsFrozen\n  fullName: Freezable.IsFrozen\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.OnChanged\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: OnChanged()\n  nameWithType: Freezable.OnChanged()\n  fullName: Freezable.OnChanged()\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.OnFreezablePropertyChanged(System.Windows.DependencyObject,System.Windows.DependencyObject)\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: OnFreezablePropertyChanged(DependencyObject, DependencyObject)\n  nameWithType: Freezable.OnFreezablePropertyChanged(DependencyObject, DependencyObject)\n  fullName: Freezable.OnFreezablePropertyChanged(DependencyObject, DependencyObject)\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.OnFreezablePropertyChanged(System.Windows.DependencyObject,System.Windows.DependencyObject,System.Windows.DependencyProperty)\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: OnFreezablePropertyChanged(DependencyObject, DependencyObject, DependencyProperty)\n  nameWithType: Freezable.OnFreezablePropertyChanged(DependencyObject, DependencyObject, DependencyProperty)\n  fullName: Freezable.OnFreezablePropertyChanged(DependencyObject, DependencyObject, DependencyProperty)\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.ReadPreamble\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: ReadPreamble()\n  nameWithType: Freezable.ReadPreamble()\n  fullName: Freezable.ReadPreamble()\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.WritePostscript\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: WritePostscript()\n  nameWithType: Freezable.WritePostscript()\n  fullName: Freezable.WritePostscript()\n- uid: System.Windows.Freezable.WritePreamble\n  parent: System.Windows.Freezable\n  isExternal: false\n  name: WritePreamble()\n  nameWithType: Freezable.WritePreamble()\n  fullName: Freezable.WritePreamble()\n"}